[music]
[applause]
Hi everyone, Yes team is glad
welcome you to our new stage
which is dedicated to the discussion hello to everyone who
joined us for the first time and those who do not
first time with us How many of these
really a lot of super what
Despite the fact that dc-cops is fresh
a new topic that does not teach at the university
compared with metapams that were on
linux or network stages participants
getting bigger and bigger Geography
spreading it can't but please ya
I hope that on our summer stage
which will be dedicated to Security
there will be more participants and spectators
by september campa we will collect a huge
a huge audience, moreover, we have
there are even permanent members of our
stages that take first place
By the way, you know that we have a man
which Linux and network attacks dragged
completely took first place there
heard but not in detail
to get to know this person
more We are even with him today
let's get free ask how he is so super
it turned out here, drag the task by the way
I wonder how you think he will master and
divici cops topic this time i think it is
such a strong participant who will master
anything super can you tell me
about the task more What awaits today
our members to our members
today waiting for three new puzzles
first Well, in general, each of these
puzzles have some problem with
information security which
needs to be removed or
exploit in the first task on
need to get familiar with the process.
how to use dependent components
when developing according to almost
no program is written from scratch
Because well, why rewrite what
already exists but so mindless
using dependencies and libraries
can lead to problems such as
licenses for these libraries or even
Well, he also finds a vulnerability in them. Here in
this task will just need with this
figure out the second task comes
like a little on the other side there you need
will find vulnerabilities and
use it in this task
the negligent developer left the legend
secrets right in the code as an administrator
gave access to
the web interface of the application will need to
find those hidden flags and execute
task in the third task you will receive in
disposition cluster gubernatis u
which has seen a sharp increase in consumption
memory and processor will need to understand
what happened and fix the leak
resources is our task
and what is the task that understands up to
mitapa
all buildings are open today after four
assignments that I understood according to the classics
the studio speaker is missing this time so
that I recommend everyone to listen because
that colleagues will definitely share individual
the ideal information you need
during the passage of tasks, that is, analysis
won't we still don't mind if sama
write some conversation and lay out
his telegram channel doesn't matter, but with his
we do not promise such analyzes
Fine
who are we going to listen to today
will help the participants in their further work with
assignments Our first speaker This is Kirill
Bochkarev infrastructure architect
information security which
will tell you about the assessment of the maturity of safe
developments in companies and our approach to
conducting such an assessment further down the list
but not by value. This is Alexey Smirnov
founder of cat scoring and
profiscope he will tell about myths and facts
in the software supply chain
providing the third speaker This is Yuri
Shabalin from Stingray
Technologies is also
he is the lead architect of sportfish
talk about the current vulnerability in
mobile apps fourth speaker
speaker Excuse the fourth speaker Danil
Kokorin web developer from the company
Jet system, he will tell you how
hacks the application and how
protect yourself from such a hack.
5 speaker This is Dmitry Evdokimov
founder and network company lantry he
tell about the classification of funds
protection of the governorates and the sixth speaker
Alina Knyazeva will be the head
directions of all Zen from the company VK
Alina share experience of building
development processes in large companies
these are our speakers
interactive
stays with the speakers We play our own game
left only grandmother, that is, we have
there will be blocka explain granny removed
the neural network will instead block with
truth or myth and truth or myth
will be including by our speakers So
that we will discuss the details, possibly personal
the lives of our participants are also you and I
we will discuss memes and throw ideas
Which meme fit you can do it
left the same in the comments
will be super Then we will have questions with
the first desks are questions that could
ask your intern and tell pasha what
such a kes Why is there an eight
in the middle of this class will be
questions here And we will be super
Curious block about ditties like you
you know how ditties are extremely positive, but
That's great
because yes today I will feel
ingots voiced by robots women proper
according to the interactives in our game is
block and also we will have 10 questions
Dixie specialists know who we are
we will create them
So if you have any questions write
comments but in general us this block
we are ready and if that Pasha is straight specifically
tormented by questions, that's how I am
spoke to our first place with makbes
I hope we succeed
a short interview and ask where he is from
knows about safety
So Our first speaker Kirill Bochkarev
[music]
Hello everyone, my name is Kirill, I work
infrastructure architect
information infrastructure
security at Jet
I started working jette department
who deals
worked with teaching complexes for a long time
time abroad returned already to work
information security center
For the last few years I have been
safe development during this time I
completed many implementation projects
tools
conducted many audits and saw how
secure development looks like
various companies and
we decided to tell you how Jack
conducts audits we report on the
framework that we created for evaluation
degree of development security
my next report today
I'll tell you why security
development is important Why is it necessary
conduct audits What tools
are used to conduct audits on
pros and cons of existing frameworks
and even less
Although there is such a large
the number of tools that have been created
best experts private companies topics
less we still decide to spend a bunch
time and create your own framework i
I'll tell you about him
I will tell you about the assessment methodology
examples of use will also show what
results will be received
companies based on audit results
first I'll tell you why it's safe
development is important
to begin with, the user does not want
confidential data became available
intruder
protection
well protected applications
competitive advantage If
polyurethane sees what the company is investing
big money safety what
data is not leaking it will be good
competitive advantage and more
users will use it
it is also obvious that it is safe
system they are more productive more
reliable and also requires less resources
to eliminate defects
related to information security
If
information security principles
previously applied
is also a decrease in economic
risks here can be cited as an example from
my life abroad
one of the companies
major telecommunications company
10 million data leaked
users
according to the results of the investigation
this company was forced to pay for
replacement driver's license for everyone
user instead of driver's license
for each user from these 10
million
accordingly you can calculate
in Russia the fine is still
not so harsh
development is important
Why is it necessary to audit
secure development
why is it needed
companies build a secure process
development using the experience of knowing their
experts, however, no matter how
experts were not experienced
no matter how many projects they have before
did anyway they need with something
compare what they built After all, when
you look at what you have now and
compare it with some framework with
some set of the world's best
Practitioner, do you understand?
didn't you miss out didn't you miss something
missed nothing important too
framework is a tool that will show
to what extent and to what extent do you follow
best world practices and finally
the last one is compliance
regulator
I will give an example of the Central Bank
makes demands on the process
secure development
for applications such as internet banking
For example
what is a framework what is a framework
set of instrument rule principles
guides together it can be called
practitioners
who help
developers to create secure
applications
some frameworks contain some
model maturity some no i slightly
I'll tell you about it later
main frameworks in more detail
in all frameworks all frameworks
consists of two major parts.
technology and processes
it is not enough for a company to introduce, for example, such
tool as static code analysis
little to buy the tool you need to
developers understood that with this
tool to do that is
developers
scanned the code with
static analysis got some
errors But the process they have not built they
don't know what to do with it and
efficiency buying efficiency
friction of such tool without process
will be extremely low
I'll tell you about those main frameworks
which are
let's start with Sim Basim is a framework
created by Synapsis
with its main goal to understand how
what does the company that conducts
who conducts this audit complies with
what she does is consistent with what
is in the industry That is, this comparison with
other companies let's say this one
framework is paid for
to conduct a certified audit
necessary
to pay money to this
the audit was carried out by the company synopsis I would
said that the main disadvantages of this
framework is what it has
no practice maturity model
high enough level
because the
on
practices that I can use for
abroad, not everything can be applied in Russia
for example, abroad for a long time already enough
cloud technologies are widely used
we have
still most of the companies sit
It is an admixture of the following framework which
about which I want to say it myself myself
this is the framework that was created
by the Avast community
he also has a huge number of practices
unlike bessim, he has
breakdown by maturity level
as for the cons, this is also practice
and not all practices are applicable in
Russia and we didn't really like the model
estimates That is, you can get levels
maturity within individual Practices
does not show at what level
maturity is the organization and
the main difference between self and bessima is that
Sim is the opinion of the industry
itself is the opinion of experts who
use that work for
development of this framework is the following
framework is the some then also young
framework that was developed
by Avast, it is used for
development processes that use
where is all the cops process
I would have it also split by
maturity level has the same problem
there is no understanding
At what level of maturity is
organization
and also an additional advantage
there is something that the dosom specifically says
what to do that is
practices up to soma are not high-level but
nevertheless
fairly limited framework
quite young and in terms of
processes, for example, there are only
three domains which sometimes
a dozen can be specific things
to be done and finally Microsoft
S9 is a framework that was created
by Microsoft which describes
who use the experience of the company
Microsoft software development
ensure it is simple understandable
there are simple practices without detailing
nevertheless, in order to
implement this Microsoft framework
recommends contacting them and doing
money
I would say the main reason why we
We all decided to spend a lot
time resources and create your
framework is what
its not clear where to start here at the dosoma
there are actually 4 levels
at every level
organizations are invited to donate a huge
number of practices and
if the company has a limited number
resources is almost always something
the company start to think maybe they
start with a hundred-dasta to train a champion
or maybe
do something else and i would say it
main main problem Why do we
decided to create their own framework
to want to get from the ideal
framework
firstly, you wanted to cover the entire
safe practice development process
were detailed
practices were used
relevant for the Russian market
we could evaluate the current organization
We could appreciate
the level to which the organization should strive
what they need to do and also an important part
is a necessary incremental
approach in order to
company
at each level they had a limited
number of things to do
for the company to move gradually
so that they
there was no such situation that they
understand where to start
So from what what practices did we include
What is the device that we
we use in the audit we took many
practice the most basima
took the documents of the abscess added a dream
There are a huge number of models
maturity from manufacturers
they all have pretty interesting
things also we decided in our course
add experience our experience and experience
customers because we had a great
quantity we understand
as a customer
the actual goals of our framework
state definition This definition
states to be, that is, where organizations
over strive
identification of initiatives that
organization needs to complete
reaching the next level
and finally
the organization must understand how much it
costs
[music]
What elements does our framework consist of?
pirate map calculation table and
pyramids of maturity pirate map is y
us was the internal name of this
element I did not
rename why pirate map
That is you soon she has a look at those
practices that make up our framework
and in fact if the company follows all
these practitioners then their prize is safe
development
further This table calculations within
calculation table is calculated
at the level of maturity within specific
Practitioner and the pyramid of maturity
The purpose of this tool is to understand what
the level of maturity is the organization
where where it aspires to exactly that
precisely the part that in many
frameworks missing
so let's start with the pirate map. It consists of
of two large parts is technology
process
technology is worth four
large parts first part is all that
related to protection
infrastructure with which it works
developer while developing code second
part of it
related directly to writing.
code of the third part After it is connected with
topics
associated with testing after
the cat was assembled before the cat
placed in a productive environment
tested and finally the last part
it's part of the program
provide a productive environment
and processes we have processes
training and connecting teams to the process
development of everything related to
formation of management requirements
functional role defects in this
domain we determine who does what on
each stage of development and finally Evaluation
effectiveness of the process of dixiasis Today
we will talk in more detail about the domain
technologies
like i said domain technology
consists of 4 large parts of the environment
development There is included under the domain
control or dependency artifacts is
artifact is what
created by the development process
image dependencies what is used
developers
when developing code
protection development environment is something with which
developer works
when creating the code It includes beat
environment control artifact registry
spring change code envelope assembly
also additionally In this subdomain we
introduced practices such as worker protection
places of the developer, I would say practice
does not directly affect the development process
code, but nevertheless it affects the overall
process on overall process safety
After all, if
workstations
on which the code is developed
not protected at all, then this
crosses out
fully
safety in code development
subdomains which
directly affect the development of the code we
consider
in detail
subdomain which
does not directly affect the development of the code
such as job security
we consider a developer on a basic
level the next subdomain is
code development is a tool that
built into paypoint maturity which we
evaluate
it's traditional stuff like
static code analysis
code analysis container analysis and so on
further after the program
security passed
assembly phase comes testing phase
At this stage, the following are used
tools like dynamic code analysis
configuration control before these
configurations will be migrated
productive environment and
functional testing and finally
after the software
passed
stage
testing
next step is exploitation
The industrial environment here we have such
practices like managing secrets
access control management which
network traffic
analysis of events of information
security and so on
go to the calculation table
domains are divided in practice practice
divided at the level
we have 5 pieces
zero starts when practice fails
used
ending at the fourth level at which
practice is developed to the maximum level
at each level of practice one or
multiple requirements
the domain is included, respectively, several
practitioner
according to the results of the calculation table
visualization is done to understand in order to
it was clear to be
can be seen, among other things, by the leader
level is this or that practice That
yes if the level is fully completed
out of demand one hundred percent
performed then accordingly practice
it turns out one hundred percent and paint
be painted green
execution practice performs
respectively, it is 0 percent and red
indication there is she most
executed respectively yellow
indication and blue if practice in
implemented to a lesser extent
Actually, this is the stage at which
ends calculation for
public frameworks
and within
calculation tables we understand the level
maturity within practices
Next We have a pyramid of maturity
we have a pyramid of maturity out of 7
steps
start zero ending on seventh
level
no centralized
centrally approved tools
every developer can use
may not use
some tools depending on
his wishes of experience and on the cosmic
level when all the instruments are
organizations are up and running
maximum at this level of organization
there are resources to implement
most
time-consuming and I would say extravagant
practice
in fact, our pyramid consists of three
the main parts are levels from zero
the second it happens at this stage
introduction of basic tools
application of basic harding but still
less at this at these stages
development
tools are not used to the maximum
That is, for example, only part of the secrets
stored in the tool
next We have levels from 3 to 5 on
which the main purpose of the organization is to
to push the boundaries
using tools to
like all the secrets
kept secret management to
make sure that
there are no secrets in the code, not in history, not in
all code base and so on and finally
after the organization
seeks
like i said they have
resources to do something
more
That is, for example, to collect
open source components on their own
sign and so on I will tell
about what is at these levels a little
later reason why we have our
pyramid arrows exactly
7 levels instead of three because we want
for the organization to be able
apply secure development practices
instrumentally to
no organization required
make a jump from zero to have them
it was possible to do it gradually
actually our pyramid of maturity
looks like this is what we have
levels Practicing levels Practicing they
tied
to specific steps of the pyramid on
zero level respectively Practitioner
No, because at this level, how do I like
I already said chaos developers do
what they want
wherein
Here
different practices
recommended for use in different
levels That is, for example, we recommend
we recommend starting
the phenomenon of instruments with control
secrets That is, it is the keeping of secrets in
code is the definition of secrets code and so
further why because one secret is he
can cross out the whole process
safe development remember
cases related to super when
administrator left a secret associated with
storage
left an account with the administration
storage in one of the scripts As a result
the attacker found this script and
actually after that
burglary was completed he received
access to all data
[music]
Also, our practices are distributed according to
pyramid unevenly That is, for example
if we take comp we recommend
start garden development on the second level
continue development on the third on
fourth and most
advanced practice already applied on
seventh level of the pyramid
Let's take a closer look at the steps of the pyramid.
detail
Let's start from level zero of self-organization
there is, as I said in the organization
no centralized use
approved
no centralized secrets
controlled
harding
which is used in the development
completed present
default settings and so on here
Developers decide what they want
use
gave the minimum level
at this level, basic ornings were completed
infrastructure limited access
conveyor from the slide and about the environment will perform
basic harding
workstations and At this stage also
appear already
depsicobs tools i.e.
secret detection
Image docker Fails canning it all
used in manual mode
automatically automatic locks
integration assemblies of the entire network on a given
stage is not done in terms of
check b
pentests can be performed at the stage
testing but still
it is not regulated
Next Next, go to the basic level
at a basic level, sast is already used
Secrets Management appears
essey all these tools they are
all SDs are built in
blocking individual assemblies
performed automatically, but
nevertheless
from the point of view of a pine, for example, any
any base it is not covered by this
tool in terms of secretariat
Same
not searched for secrets throughout
codebase and so on
in terms of checks and B
periodically scanned
infrastructure environment regularly
conducted pentests in nature and
periodically but this is also not
regulated can be carried out
after the organization
implemented the main tools
we go levels from third to 5 that is
at this level already
applied such enough
advanced practices how to use
approach all configurations
central storage processing
logs a higher level for example for
in order to
the developer could make a comet
approval required at least
two people
And also our zones are increasing
covering basic tools up to
complete, that is, for example, at this stage
we keep all the secrets secrets
in terms of checking b
checks are automated
functions are performed regularly
productive infrastructure scanning
environment is made regular and
regulation of pin tests against
and finally level 6 7
At this stage, after the company
implemented all the main tools
the maximum level of their use
for example, the organization as I said already
all possible secrets are kept
means all change secrets in the code
nowhere
using the entire database is scanned here
you can go now
in the most advanced practice but with
I can say that not all of these levels
and all organizations need these levels then
present at this level
organizations can collect Open Source
components to sign them yourself
use dynamic secrets with
limited
crowded access and in terms of verification
B
most of them are automated
actually this slide example
using our framework
Can
based on this warehouse understand
that there is an organization that there is no organization
And where should they strive, that is, this
organization for example no practice at all
pin tests they don't have a tool for everything
crisis is where to start, that is, on
at the moment they are doing a big
part practice level 1 and some
number of Level 2 Practitioners i.e.
Accordingly, they need to close practices
level 1 and work on level practitioners
pyramid It allows you to understand on what
level of maturity is the organization To
is this the main goal
according to the results
conducting an audit based on the results
preparing the pyramid proper
organizations
organization can prepare
roadmap i.e. Here is an example
using the roadmap for
for audit That is, they are recommended
inject secret detection Secrets
Management scanning docker files
images and also outside of functionality
testing
testing the information function
security in the testing phase
[music]
completion I would like to say that on
at the moment we are holding
still testing our framework
on various customers
we get quite positive feedback.
the less the framework does not stand still
all the practices of which are listed in
this framework they
periodically reviewed we review
What new trends are emerging
For example, now many companies
consider
use of artificial intelligence
For
threat modeling i.e. this practice
Perhaps we will include in the next version
our framework also
We are working on calculations
visualization and actually I think through
six months we will have a lot more
better
according to the results
the customer understands where he is now where he is
move and what investment to him
necessary is the main purpose of our
framework
Thanks to all
[music]
Thank you
Let's start from the beginning You are very
talked a lot about femborg about our
development Tell me please Can you
be planning to lay out some
template in the world or articles on swag or
already done so that the listeners
get acquainted we think about it
Because the main frameworks are
still available
a huge number of people and the more
the number of people affects the development
the more i get him the more he
it gets better so we think
thinking about making it available
Yes there are prospects for what's coming to me
go finish it of course
And now without the participation of the community
Compared to other frameworks
which everyone knows if the organization decides
surprise yourself with this framework
There they are all over what advantages it has
get in the end
But if the organization is audited by
everything and itself
then they'll get the visualization they'll get
charts
but firstly they will have problems with that
to
interpret what is written
because many practices they are high
level they concern not only the hexicops
and they will have a problem with privatization
what to start with why to start with
this is why you need to start with this
Thank you
Come on what do you think At what level
pyramid is maturity I know come on
on the second
participated in
glue on this tool we have them
interrogated pretty addicted passed
great job have questions
To
applications that are available
requirements for the level of trust
two requirements can be met
ways either you spend every year
audits you verify the code
you develop a bunch of documentation or the Central Bank
proposed a second option
since all internet banks
use let's create a syncops i.e.
being audited being audited for
specific version when audit
actually ends at the bank already
released
The Central Bank proposed to audit the process
secure development This is something that
concerns
results of how they are this application
develop if safe
develop something and the output is
application There are a huge number
requirements a lot of restrictions but still
less where it goes cool
I'm sorry I read I don't see
in terms of compliance and requirements
regulator for safe development
what level of instrument you are
provided necessary
I think here too
for the most part, this is the base level. There is no
all instruments
taken into account by the Central Bank not about everything not about everything
the details said I think it's about
level 2 plus
Ok thanks for the materials that
voiced by Cyril we plan that
we will share materials So stay tuned
our telegram channel and Ill tell you right away
there will be a survey soon
which we would very much like to pass
now let's get back to our game.
Yes, she will appear on the screen
Choose a category
explaining granny
discussing memes
and the most basic question seems to me
now the first batch is not really needed
Let's explain the octopus to granny
let's start
safe part
What is a container
[laughter]
come on come on now if only if granny
didn't know anything about development
she knows okay bead
programmed And you know what it is
ip address
I think I'm sure that granny needs this
What do you do Tell me at work
I provide container security
Which
What is a container
limited area Maybe I don't know so
How to say a limited area in
operating system
so this container turns out well the same
like a marine only in some other form
you understand that if she is in Pobol language
then she can pickle cucumbers in
one bank
carry cucumbers to another jar conditionally in
another environment like rather
is it possible yes can you please click us
Thank you let's have some meme
with a parrot
So the situation which
[music]
[laughter]
I feel like this when I've done everything
everything is ready the script is written I don't know or
back forehead charged and then comes
some insight from the team that something
could go wrong and
it doesn't look like it's a feeling
meet something else yes it is
comes who breaks
that were formed before
it's like when it comes it comes
edit presentation in 15 minutes
[laughter]
Familiar situation familiar case Cyril
Thank you
there are no more comments in the chat, we are waiting for these
presentation naturally articles or
framework described as a template for the world
looking forward to joining the community
so so so so so so so
further, Alexey Smirnov will tell us about
supply chain myths facts
software all eyes on
screen
[music]
Hello everyone I'm Alexey Smirnov today
talking about myths and facts and joys
supply chain woes what's up with that
happens and how to avoid it
I am the founder of the compositional system
analysis of clscoin just the same
system that looks and is called
monitor the quality of your chain
supply and for the safety of components
who pass through it doing
quite a long time commercial development
software for many years
taught programming and
We have been analyzing for a long time.
source codes in their various variations from
classification of source codes up to
source code security including
using machine learning about this
we write stories in our Good channel
mining within the Open Data community
Science connect happens there
Interesting
respectively
But today we are here to talk
about what lies in our
supply chain
What is a chain in general?
supplies Many people think that the chain
supplies It's only third-party
components that we use in our
actually it's not so it's yours
own code is third party code
as if all together and the components and
libraries are the tool that you
attract during the assembly process, that is, in
including This is the whole story of rhetoric and
so on is a set of processes
managing these artifacts and all this
together makes the same chain
supplies
Today we will talk more
of course about borrowed and
attracted third-party components then
yes, we'll talk about the same Open
Source Open Source pretty much it
over 200 million projects worldwide
open source which
developed by a large number of authors
They are developers and, accordingly, there
5 million packages 75 million versions
and so on and so on like
many, many developers write open
github code claims over 100 million
at least once one commit, so we counted by
github made 70 million people at
this
regularly participates in the development
open source about five million
a person almost like the population of my
native city of st. petersburg
less we all grow more and more
downloads of open
components it From year to year
increases twice and But not everything is so
relatively speaking
changes proportionally, for example, for
last year the number increased 13 times
known supply chain attacks such as
since the subject of our conversation is
there are increased cases
Taipe 8 confusion and other types
cheating the user let's say so
developer of diopser
so that he catches the malicious
component or component is particularly vulnerable
let's say packages with malware each
month more than about 500 are detected
month in all languages again
programming if you look appeared
last year we have a new term
currently applicable to Russia
but in general very international
countermeasures that is sabotage
targeted attacks against
developers specific users
countries are not necessarily
Russia and such packages also appeared
there were few but they are here about this in
everyone about what
we have a lot going on pimping
and everyone takes very different actions
so we collected let's say so from the fields from
audits from product practice
directly the case with which we
encounter when communicating with our
contractors and would like a little of them
disassemble debunk what us
ask at conferences these
questions We are studying today, that is, the Myth
is it a fact or is it
the first one is the simplest here rather
not a myth and not a fact, it's something in the middle
That is, everyone thinks that everything should be stopped
Pack and hide your head in the sand
the simplest That is, when we talk about
that we have malicious code in
our projects Accordingly, we
we will do we will organize simply
conditional clean repositories This means
that's nothing new, we don't add it
we will be an old one, well, most likely, too
we will not check, that's why I want
disassemble this case a little
means what is happening stops
we have a lot of updates
news was for the past year that in
such-and-such package index 100 packages
appeared malicious here such and such
these packets steal data these steal and
sent where it is not necessary at all, that is, and
scarecrow it was it well, just out of
each iron but the news outlets they
directly dispersed dispersed dispersed this
history and
my my opinion that well not quite maybe
be deservedly so let's say because
there are more problems than they write about
this news is not for that a little bit
focused attention But there is news
news therefore
The first action of people who
I'm in charge of security they say
so we won't have the whole update anymore
okay and what happens there is a headache
developer pain in security o
immediate Ozerov yes that is
and both individually and
joint that one cannot
develop using the latest versions
libraries others are forced to check
each library for statics and
very non-obvious algorithms, let's say
there are a lot of checks of these packages
check and check there is no life
enough to check the entire pump for static
until the developers themselves
really follow the practices
safe development and
respectively
ate injections continued to eat the cactus
doesn't mean it's bad, but
this is the first action taken
people and but also from hopelessness because
that they didn't have the right one in stock
ready technique to work
and didn't have the right tools to
maintain proper cleanliness
components that fall which
would allow direct
order ours there proxy repositories ours
component base as a whole and
respectively in this case like this
fix would like to give Just a set
small recommendations
that is, yes, the problems are known and understandable
as if there is something to rely on
there are Sky decision criteria
which came out last year
That is, they are not about Open Source, but they
also suitable there is a testing technique
update azteca wonderful which
left Don't have to follow these
methods from start to finish
we look at practice and rely on it
and create our own methodology for
which we move, that is, the one that we
comfortable and convenient does not mean that
you have to go across there, but that doesn't mean
what needs to be done is all
recommendation and methodologies As a framework from
it can be taken and built from the right
steps that are enough for you
the facility where you produce your
juice According to what needs to be done with
the instrument's point of view needs to be adjusted
proxy repositories already finally who is it
not configured just not to lose your
dependencies on older builds including
it is necessary to introduce controls for the proxy
repository and for compositional
analysis accordingly if if such
was not and it is very important to build
correct logical policies are not
block all new components i.e.
better not to block all components
block new components
there are some that came out relatively recently
well, that is yesterday today
a week ago i.e. look after that
so you don't have there too maybe
be old components But that's what I
I will talk more today
Accordingly, then we check
update already as if we have
chain control verification tool
delivery, he worked for us and said No
listen dear here you need to check
of course, we take something to check the statics
conditionally take to the source or take
the gray box is
combining statics and dynamics is an approach
Of course, it will be the most effective, but in
parts directly harmful to you
will be more behind the eyes
it is better not to run dynamics on malware
of course, well adjust accordingly
processes build tools
Solve the problem Great Great let's go
next about the next myth and here
a bit of a repetition
previous conditional exit udo is what
against the creature is the worst thing there is
this is what we were dispersed by the news
again, from every iron they said here
bad programmers there 30 buildings
writes about how bad he wrote
some library and thereby expressed
your protest
accordingly, of course, protests
she is scary and accordingly they come out
people who express slogans
directly in that community in
which perhaps they shouldn't have
still express
we had cases of identification
third-party packages that are really
were malicious code
politicized malware, that is, these
there are very few components, that is, this thing
that is, my fingers are enough to
show how many
there are other packages that include
yourself slogans here it is important to understand that in
depending on how serious
you build your security here is important
understand that today is the slogan, and tomorrow it is
maybe ndv and that's how it should be
Being prepared is important to keep track of
so this story needs to be correct
way to control but that's just
tip of the iceberg is when you protest
the creature is directly explicit with specific authors
tell everything
but the full picture is that
that is not a politicized malware
goes out there monthly
more than 500 statistics per month
sometimes there are peaks of one and a half thousand in
month open in batch indexes
such a story is revealed that's all
of course it's very annoying
trying to clean up as much as possible
package indexes, including
signal this to the system
supply chain control respectively
This is also something that should not be allowed
it is important not to forget that the protests
not so scary Although also scary But how
the orders would be simply incomparable
respectively fix Here is also simple
we look at point one like this
check update but build
convenient and logical policies to
it was comfortable for everyone to work
next next such interesting myth
which grows roots a little to
such a decision as before Panda bothabu ko
everything
people were taught to always roll on
the latest version and therefore in the community
sometimes such a story flashes what if
we will update to the latest
versions of third-party code, then everything will be
safe But that's exactly what we're talking about
today we'll talk And what's going on here
impact not only on safety Here
there is an influence in general on development in
overall and at speed, because if you
you will always roll madly on the most
latest versions first this
simply the top of development, that is
and you will spend time updating
API Well, that is, compatibility with all
these third party components which
endlessly endlessly renewed because
that will be constantly updated
autotests will load on
testing rise and it
simply unsafe because
new version they are so thorough they are
are checked and accordingly in the news
there may be those same surprises with not
discovered vulnerabilities
check all new packages for
security with the help of the same statics
or speakers you're unlikely to be
Again, this is about labor costs.
Here each item from labor costs
so roll on the latest
version It's not quite reasonable reasonable
will update the packages actually on
necessary and safe versions of exactly what
saves test development time
security and ops, that is, and you need
will choose a comfortable model
politician
and an exception corresponding to what you like
I say I've said many times
to speak so as not to nightmare
developers
do not install an update younger than a month old
Obviously no one dies from this.
will outlast the old content packs
put like yes that is not like and
we remove it from there, that is, because
old package In general, no one needs
either updated or shot, but that's all
depends on the project here it is very like this
conditional clause next recurrent
check old assemblies check what you have
us where when was going to what
components then we look
how is it going on with us
the process of integration with statics, including
yes i.e. do we send packets
we configure this process for statics not
we just blocked everything and for now
this pack of statics is not tested, we are not
let go no that's all it should be
Precisely specific tasks and understandable Flow
decision and parsing for security and
it is important to set up a convenience exception so that
developers give them time to make changes
don't block everything let them
Develop Yes Components Contains
critical vulnerability, but
how would they give time to correct if we
block and put the development again
just in a stupor arises here
questions
next
fix all vulnerabilities found
they said they meet
actually there are such organizations
by type of activity, including
set the security policy
all vulnerabilities found must be
eliminated
and not so much in your own code
but also in third-party code and but unfortunately
only they don't swipe the code back
spread And of course they have everything
works very well how are you
understand accordingly
this rechecking approach is absolutely
the total elimination of absolutely all
Vulnerabilities Yes it exists Yes
there really are those very units
who cry including transitive
dependence and straight crying and, as it were
rebuild packages impose Fixes
do some kind of protection there on the Application
Firewall and so on That is, not
you can definitely fix it in the code
be conditionally imposed funds But by the
no less, as it were, and comes to success
further
to come to success of course everything
use different types of prioritization
yes, that is, there by the presence of an exploit on
type of defect There vectors of criticality
and so on someone might be enjoying
epss or some alternative is
Exploit Edition
Here, accordingly, this is all this is all
maybe, but it doesn't make it any easier for you
you just get a job
the priority you deal with is A
task Disassemble all the vulnerabilities you have
remains and whether it is necessary to do this at all and
many who actually with this
faced unfortunately do not know much
basic definition and concept of how
attack surface let's ask ourselves
our application for development for everyone
whether the vulnerable component is generally
attack surface If you respond to
this question you will remove your own work
at least once there in 5 in 10 it all depends on
technology and so on, everything is very
conditional interest, but what if you have
how would you shoot from the attack surface
there components
then your application Clearly stops
be to this extent understandable
somehow cleverly something to use for
this you have additional checks
yes that is including you have
correct dynamics and so on
So the next Aspect which is also
about this story is that many
think about what is dangerous vulnerabilities
is only in directives
dependencies is generally also mine somehow
favorite story is
everyone thinks we will update everything now
us in the directive, everything is cool with us, but
the reality is that you are all fine
understand that
vulnerable components are positive
transitive dependency is dependency
your directive dependencies Everything is very
just respectively you have and
appear
transitive vulnerabilities themselves
which also need to be somehow repaired and
of course it is being repaired, there are approaches
again that is either patching it
update it's Application Firewall it's
configuration change or even just me
sorry sawing third party
component that is vulnerable but you have it
you do not need but again the question
is it on the surface
question from the previous conditional etude so
according to statistics, 85 percent
vulnerabilities the application itself
is in transitive
addictions and the saddest and nastiest
that they might actually be there
operated according to any
actually
and they will tell you all that through a transitive
with 3 4 levels of nesting quite imagine everything
can be operated together with about it
let's talk more clearly what we have
server room, let's say so
programming languages or technologies
as if we have directives
there are relatively few transitive ones
Well, that is, this is a hundred several hundred then
there is Java Python and other languages
programming when we talk about
used to be called frontens now it's
us like general-purpose languages
Just like typescript javascript is
1000 dependencies behind this all by hand
follow here you need the right one
automation is therefore beyond transitive
dependencies are important to follow again
preferably automatically uses our
the most beloved notation with bombs is all
record and check regularly
about pin testing, including
I would like to show just a slide
simple
Here the picture forgot to sign it Lock
for G is the depth of Lock for G
my favorite picture what depth
occurrences of Lok Fuji in the dependency graph
here in all maven projects But this one
that is, up to level 10 We also
may be vulnerable already meet yes then
is and will even be operated on
seventh level and sixth and that's even
peak on the fifth exploitation is possible
does not mean that always and does not mean that you
this is generally relevant because
cost in a closed circuit but still
less important to understand that not only through
directive dependency can be produced
operation In addition, additionally
it is worth noting that I am now approximately there
in Java brought, as it were, for food the same
history is library saw library
which processes the image very
she is very simple, but she has the whole crust on
axes are written and respectively
you come across this library
whenever you upload your data
passport or something else to some
form, that is, perhaps the developers
are not directly used but use it
through a wrapper because wrappers are for
this library a great many This
means that you have a saw in that
Transit A itself in the library in this
dozens of vulnerabilities have already been found
just the same in the same predatory code a
which actually allow
directly executing the code on
server that allow you to drag
memory data information
about paths paths paths files and
according to all this
vulnerable versions come to you
library hackers who are trying
upload image with incorrect
data and this library will not
you are more likely to be
in directive dependencies that's why
need to watch it carefully
small bonus because we are so
sorted out a bit exactly how
such as some kind of mythology
supply chain security fact sheet
how you want to do something useful but not
quite maybe for
Siber Camp Please forgive me
the organizers would like to say about
lawyers because we are talking about
security chain practice
Yes supply chain and protection practice We
we always speak in the format
cybersecurity then actually But with
all these components is still very important
work as a lawyer in order to
follow the licensed frequency like this
actually
Now I beg your pardon Yes so
actually with the help of the same
toolkit you have configured for
tracking and control of delivery
Of course you can help your
lawyers to follow
missing licenses behind virus
third party licenses
components with export restrictions
Help the lawyers They are waiting for your help
developers obey you, I'm talking about
bezopasnikov but
actually
we need to help lawyers give them a tool
it's just so so into space
message
this is where I end
directly myths and facts now we
let's move on to the conclusion here
to say about the next What do we have there
there should have been a survey actually and it was
would be really cool its now fast
skip
answer and analyze answers
directly discussions after the report
so now colleagues will launch
survey and we will definitely analyze
results are interesting to see
we'll check another myth and then we'll see
what happens so that's actually the one
the tool i'm talking about
it is important for you to monitor the repository proxy
it is important for you to keep track of what you have
is in the pipeline, it is important for you to follow
behind what is in your original
codes because
everything in the supply chain is not so simple
not a one-liner because if you will
make a new call, as I told you in
proxy blocking stories
repositories then you will have
constant voltage between
developers seks and so on Because
that there will be constant reshuffling of tasks
unlock me such and such a component
unlock this But you have to spend
additional verification and so on
so this story should be here
uniform throughout the development cycle
first some politicians then others
policy here third policy and that
that something is blocked and so on
you still need to notify what is called
gradually first warned that is
as if the hardest blocked
further through warning lock
further already at the final assembly this is about
what did we say that it is not necessary to nightmare
developers, it is important to set up thoughtfully and
correct policies for each cycle and
stage
and the supply chain is important for this
just follow it does not mean that you have
will be a super safe product but you won't
Stop your development
will overhead on designing you not
spend too much on it
time and at the same time you will observe
let's say the canons of safety
someone has a sister, someone is weaker, but
anyway it's possible to do it
That's why
methodical correct methodical
instrumental reinforcement of practice
supply chain security is essential
it makes life easier for everyone and business and se
and opsom Thank you very much for your attention C
you were Alexei Smirnov with me you can
contact in telegram We have
we write a channel about code analysis on
Youtube
telegram And on YouTube we have a lot of different
reports that
you can look at the topic just the same
all possible issues of delivery analyzes
code and all thanks
[music]
Thank you with apologies for the fact that the lawyers and
etc. It seems to us the same
What the hell can you do on eBay is this
so there is no other type
exists so everything that concerns
interactions with related colleagues
lawyers with developers is what
also needs to be understood
topic and it seems to me even a whole report about
this would be super relevant
recently encountered a problem with
gp3 license and thought How can we solve it
Come for a consultation
here really really
interesting topic very important
close and throw the same
bridges Well, because we understand that
here we have a tool, its like about
supply chain analysis who us
interested in the supply chain of course
not only those people are the most obvious, but
and including the league jumped a lot of legal
no one listens, well, that is, because
they are not as scary as it is safer
not so you go not only does not listen
the situation is literally the following here you are
say you can't do that
maybe we'll do it to the left and that's it
resolved No
correct dialogue in this part
so this is important here.
in fact the question is literally the first in
chat was about where to get merch
just write to me personally as if we are with you
let's agree, here we have merch coming out
series is of course the most important question
today Yes merch comes out in series
and Yes, we sometimes give contests and launch
we are the simplest
speak at a conference where you can join us
come up just drag along to chat with us
without called obligation
solved now Pasha Come on your complex
questions
there were so many things I didn't even know about
suspected Here, for example, about transitive
dependencies especially Here on that slide
where is clever James
deep deep but uh how much at all
there is a high probability that this
transitive dependency with some
some kind of vulnerability can get into
as a result, the attack surface can be
it's still what it is, well, what's there
eat by eat his addiction which him
are needed And in these dependencies there are more but
they are for this in the depths somewhere there
they work far away
generally not very important, but here How
not everything is said so clearly
there is a story that
transitive dependency falls on
high probability attack surface
Well, that is, but the big question, as it were
What technology What application and so
further and so on here Log it is straight good
shot but the charm of what is from him
it was possible to close the applicational then
there is quickly and immediately but the vulnerabilities
which I mentioned today in part
image analysis processing
images Pilot story yes when you
loads an image with meta tags that
the right way we should
interpreted I'm still possible
we are not a Firewall developer, but I
not sure if Application Firewall
inspects so deeply
What
he will understand me that there are malicious tags
exploitation of the vulnerability of this library
and there
vulnerability is even worse than in G and Well
we are also preparing material
analytically in this regard, that is
affected 8 percent of all Java packages
open history with vulnerabilities in Pilot
affected about four percent of this
too much Well, that is, it's a lot
it would be clear all there sites on python But
who without pictures say no one with big
they are all there and therefore
This is what is important to protect against
just install safe versions
defend yourself there
will not help
Are there any public
known cases Here are such Attacks through
transitive dependencies
have I now unfortunately name
I won't name the company, but it was
shoved encrypted about it were
articles were directly shoved by cryptographers
through Positive That is, it's all relevant
you have a huge number today
wonderful guests invited to
savingcamp, and among them there are
white hackers that I think you can
talk about how to use
transitive dependencies and how
happens successfully even without critical
level Actually
how then to protect yourself from this But here
it is clear that depending on our direct
we can update the floor, but what is there
further is how to get to it
and make it safe there
wonderful question I'm a little bit today
that touched there the story lies in
that Yes, you can update but
transitive will be
most of this issue resolves
answer to another question directly
located or on the surface Well, what am I
said there 85% in Transit
is Yes Okay understandable but no matter who
of them hit the surface of the attack went
checked marked out if we have it there
appropriate call how ever we are there
removed this problem That is, we have
there was the same risk of acceptance
To whom everyone has been talking for so long
consultants Here we are accordingly
did everything great
remained in the positive campaign different then
is either if it is real
located and operated, and so on
means either we
we have a fixed move yes that is we
we begin to put in a conditional host from
repositories your version of this library
There and so on Either we protect ourselves
the same firewall or if all the same
she's not on the attack surface or on
attack surface But in general it can
be needless question exception
lead lead resection procedure here
and accordingly remove this component
for this go easier now already started
appropriate mechanisms appear in
in particular, a little less than a month ago
there was a story that we have guys in
Russia made history for
nodes for nodes as if to be able to
manage dependency list i.e. not
row all over these thousands here
this is me, don't put the package again
manager modern all well latest
they allow even including says yes
install this library but overlay it
patch it can be registered already in the manifest
Great Well, that is, it's both great and
problems because people who don't
they also use security
these functions and they are so yeah we
wrote a module and now a patch to it
patch patch like why do so well
interesting case But for another
reporting
Well depending
and vulnerabilities here they are somehow else
more or less clear But from the point of view
licensed frequency of this Legal
therefore in general
These are some very few
some big companies do it
attention or is it still such a topic
relevant to everyone and
Don't know
users Well, rather, the company
which, in principle, to say their own
development For the most part, also about this
and too cares or somehow accept
How it works Well it's first
a matter of culture let's let's
I would answer as a developer
who I was at the time and even now something
I remember as if the story is that you
create your own code within
companies are great you have everything there
its clear with the rights so that they dont give it away
given and so on you take a third-party
code as if people also expressed their own
opinion and entered into an agreement with you in the form
licenses they wrote that they allow
do with this source code the second as
Whatever restrictions Let's
First of all, let's think about respect for
market participants people have done with the help of
their tool you have improved your time to
Market But because you don't have to write
this is from scratch, this is one side of how
would be like that, conditionally, as it were, well
such a development
as
some kind of introvertism Yes, well, that is, in
such Key on the other hand there is a question
ligala but directly real not not that
I now said it like it's real
treaties Well, that is, this is the present
an agreement like it's not some kind
filkina letter which is just in
repositories dangling it's real
the story behind which, as one of mine said
a longtime developer for this can be found
and finds quite a lot of these cases and
in the world and in Russia and so on and all this
legally in Russia, including that is,
us according to the Civil Code, everything is equalized there, everything
cool equate and so on here
Tomorrow I have a round table there on one
another conference just about
licensed open floor so
we will also share links but with a point
view of what is important no matter small
large in general, not very much, as it were
fundamentally because if
small company but you are doing
export it is very important for you not to take
some library with export
restrictions are necessary because well in
sell the other to Iran or Iraq A
such know such license types
licenses that say that
it is impossible and there is an export
US regulation there are about 18 of them
these are types of licenses these are not libraries these are
like a license, let's raise a whole bunch more
licensed and understand that there is not
only Iran and Iraq there North Cuba
Korea and so on, that is, it is clear that
hardly e you to north korea yet
exhibit your services but nonetheless
as if there are such stories there is a story
when there is no license because
the same developer did not have
appropriate culture Well, that is, he
I just wrote like this and let it be
And for this, too, there are types of licenses.
to somehow outline it, but he even
did not attach it when there is no license
it means what's going on developers
didn't say what to do and what not to do
the base agreement is included if we
dragging a walker he has a base there
license agreement which is not
attached to the repository it says that
if the code is without a license, then it means
The author and the interviewer agreed that
written in this agreement it's there well
this type can be read in this
format respectively if there is no license
you have to write that friend Attach
please license And here is the developer
who are not very familiar with what
generally start somehow to approximately
navigate in that's how to him these
components what what can he
use what not Well how are you first
Start for some understanding in here in
this
So we have a selection of your
licenses actually in general what to read
on our posted I can throw a link
if someone writes to me Yes, I'm not very
prepared with qr codes, but actually
this is in the channel Good mining we are talking about it
we wrote and will write two years ago
made a course, I talk about it everywhere and we
have read it several times already
by licensing open by it
open course But we haven't finished it yet
now we will add it for production
and an open course will be posted on
he has very strong licensing
mentors
number of
Free Software Castes
colleague support
Well, as if the people who are in this
understand accordingly it will be
such a proven good course will
pull up useful and important cool and
finally about licenses in the chat was
question about virus license slide
mentioned What is a virus
yes, fortunately, at least we are there and as they say
we work in KB
virus license in this case
meaning the same license
refers to the apelevtus, that is, it
license now Ill say it differently
In general, the terms of these licenses are our
the most favorite there is a jeep 2 3 and so
further These are the same licenses that If
you use it on the side and
distribute your
you owe your code to the aggregate
open access to works
there are features from license to
licenses somewhere open in the open
access is understandable under the same license
that's why it's called viral what is it
as if it infects you a little, as if you
even have to open but in different
licenses differently somewhere it's on
first call
or let's go to court said
Well, these are the stories they have in Russia
well, it happens
let's say that
the presenter was actually on YouTube yet
discussion question seduced I think
what you can listen to and invite in that
number in your channel you will make a post there
submit all questions
on YouTube we did a poll if possible
see in his result I would be glad
this is the final discussion about
the question was that you are sure that everything
your dependencies go through a proxy
repositories, if available, and results
following Yes
26%. no 26 percent and strongly
I doubt that all 47%. great, there you go
which was required to prove
really a very sore subject.
Thank you very much for letting me know
answers to such a wonderful question
The problem is that when introducing a proxy
repository check developers
there are workarounds How to bring
components past him or they are there or they
were already in development there somewhere assembly
and so on and they do not get into the proxy and
they also do not get tested in this
case and gather there locally and all AND
it means just carried past our
walls past our conditional firewall
but thank you very much colleagues who answered
very happy super us yes timing straight
so plump became suggest then
open your game
command your game on the super screen
well choose
[music]
Let's Truth or Myth
that's the title of the topic
[laughter]
So programmed that it was no longer
very interesting straight folding story
programmer, but nothing
I don't want to say anything bad
I wanted to apply where Well, that is
solve problems and so on and so forth
went to us from the fur, as it were, became his
worked as a mathematician and astrometer
time series analysis there actually
in astronomy, not so much, as it were, but
doing time series analysis on
sphere That's the whole story that is
any interesting mathematics first
queue and lots and lots of data because
basic is always a lot of data
interestingly it is applied and then
was following u path with passion
analysis of source codes that are not
only about safety but also about
quality
licenses as we know about analysis
all kinds of artifacts and here we are with
you met And so
count in the shelf
famous astronomers arrived because
as we know Olegbertons is also an astronomer
and specialty too
was And I ask for the next points
No
It's not true, why did she bounce me
I'm trying to remember this
Hudson Oh super Yes like that
ok let's go next point
Next question
Well let's have some meme let it be
squid again I don't know it's hard
something is not very difficult Let's disassemble
Describe this situation
here, of course, it will be more difficult
listen to it like
full joke
ship or plane and respectively
someone on an island wearing some kind of cape
looking somewhere but it's hard for me
memes I am at all
unpopular for me is mvp which is not
Yes, for me it's nothing more than
Vice versa
this is something more already the collapse of something
there is water there is another ship there and there
everything has already happened there everything has gone and this one
ran into but was too self-confident and
too pirate
OK
Super Then I think we let you go
Thank you very much Alex can be found
in his community chats write to ask
questions Thank you Yes Thank you very much We
we're going on a break and come to us now
connect to answer questions
this discovery is because makbest us in 3D
I correctly call this
Sounds like Macbeth
implied that is, like Shakespeare
ok this is super straight unexpected just
I really expected to see you in Zoom
ok can you please tell me how
you learned about Cyber Camp about cybercamp
in general, I learned from colleagues and about the most
the first one that was large-scale turns out
but alas, I did not have time
register
component, too, I solved the tasks that
were here for all public well and
I took the hoodie
Are you planning to visit us this year?
september camp Well, in general, in the plans
there are all the more like how it will be possible without
contest fly in if
plans for that's what doso is ready
I would say that the topic is for me after all
now if Linux networks are more or less still then
the same where all the cops after all
echoes so to speak I'm familiar That's but
in general, I think it will be possible to read and I
I think we will do everything
how much is it Question ok super and
so clean you know because of
comments Are you somehow on our
slippers in general No well that is How
way count if i apply
cunning that can be met does not seem
Anywhere
In general, I would say that from cheating Here
it didn't even make sense to me
in the past Well, that is, the point was
that in general those tasks that were theirs
could have googled to find
something like this and smoothly come to
solving something like this how close
what do you think now which in general
passes as to what we
we organize on a skate, I would say this
rather something else, after all, that is, to
example for the task Yes plus or minus ttf
to search for flags, for example, by pinning
Now it was already something distant then
there is in fact in the cef you are looking for flags where
whatever, but here, as it were, a specific topic
was and all these places of fixing while you
I didnt google the most where you can gain a foothold
you won't find any job anymore
I remember or liked everything
I liked the task where there was some
log storage with the web Well, that is
the network part is where exactly that is
on the virtual machine it rises and already in
further you are looking for it there and
deal with the new software and now
such a provocative question
least liked
I would say that this is the task where I was
Kwaka in my opinion it was just strange
that is, initially where it was necessary
configure SPF and listen to traffic constantly
I had problems all the time
with a virtual machine and me as a whole, initially I
I just looked and I ran into problems.
unless I just walked away for 5 minutes and didn't
exhaled, I would quit altogether
OK, got it
desire to eat
in general, it would probably be more interesting
maybe if the task was in
In this case, three tasks, as if they
open gradually
I would say maybe do Explicit
the time limit on the task, that is, here
so that a person would not be such that
as if we have declared time there time on
problem solution two hours That's it but it's like
would be recommended, that is, it turns out you
you can sit there for a week
conditionally for two days, always, as it were, and can
to be if there is this restriction
us as if it turns out a person
motivate just the same in the moment
figure it out and figure it out to the end
in this vein, I even understood the meaning
that when you pass for not too
take a long time to remove points that you can
get it affects the ranking in that
including I thought the rating does not affect at all
time to solve the problem how much is correct
after all Well, in general, yes, we balanced
still in terms of how much you
flags found it's true it's true
ok ok maybe chat if you have
have questions then super I will look A
can you tell me which one you have
education I have a bachelor's degree
ska not information security
master's degree in information security
that is, specifically on the topic and you pass
to our stages with friends with colleagues or
with colleagues we go through That is, we have me
I would even say some competitive
the share is the most separately at work yes
No
that is, we have
for example, there are guys with whom
I clearly know that they can do anything
much faster than me but they can either
make a mistake or something and it's very nice how
to go around and say sorry, I decided
more correct but longer Okay And if you
most likely when you will
you will recruit a team at the CAMP
Choose from work colleagues or there I
I would say ok this is really great
you don't just understand us, you don't just understand us
metab and people at work get jealous and then
will come to our camps together and will uh
break rating ok super it's straight
cool and let's not know about you
inspiration customized can be eat
some rituals and before the task
sit down to decide
I would say there are no rituals
stock up on tea biscuits and in principle
you can start to decide ok thank you
Thanks a lot
we hope that you will be at home or on
work before opening
By the way, the task will open at 4 o'clock after
completion Thank you very much
I would like to clarify the team if we have
time or we announce next
timing speaker
because Pasha and I can
talk about something okay we have more
time is space for you
this is the universe
what the universe is in fact Yes
I've always wondered that's the players
who pass the task more
interesting to hack something or vice versa
investigate Well, we actually got together
the community is mixed up and it seems to me
most of the tasks were still about
I can't answer this question
was more about hacking or about
investigation So if you want
write to us in the chat what tasks you do not want
enough or what do you like more then this
Feedback would be great too
By the way, here are a few questions.
where Anton Gavrilov was with us but
is behind the scenes Yes, it is Anton
Gavrilov chose everyone I think
speakers and there was almost a casting
the director who chose the reports
listened to all our colleagues generally speaking
inside it goes like a casting
director
Yes, it turns out He is in the office now
it would probably be right to say all
to interrogate because to subscribe to
its impossible for him, hes something with Alexei
discusses with Alina In general, enjoys
which is there Okay what else do you need
say on questions yes fly our
Telegram leave yours there too
comments feedback including
there will be a poll soon
did not start, I probably did not see
I already nods started yes super mean
just jump into the chat
pass our question Yes, at four they will open
all our assignments
What else can be said
what else
I just looked at the record as usual
presentations will also be posted if we
share it also on our channel record
will also remain on YouTube That is
can be viewed at any time
here I think
we classically rummage all the information
which the speakers
So
Fine
ok in that case
We present Yuri Shabalin
tell about the current addiction in
mobile applications for 22 years
[music]
Hello friends Hello everyone Thank you for
performance
I'll introduce myself again, my name is
Yura Shabalin I General Director
stingra technologies and very
many and very often check and
mobile app for security
we find there a huge number of the most
various vulnerabilities and
frequently occurring ones I get you today
I'll try to tell
Unfortunately my report will not be due
for nothing rather scrambled eggs I wanted to say
many many common vulnerabilities
found in applications
But when I made my sunset he
turned out to be about two
half an hour I realized that unfortunately
time is limited I hope dear
colleagues will call me again and we can
do second series therefore structure
the report will be quite simple we
let's talk about something that is more common today
met us in vulnerabilities at twenty
second year in those applications that we
analyzed automatically and manually, but
to start
think about what
lies in our mobile applications and
why actually
I'm talking about it today and
in principle I am engaged in mobile
security
Unfortunately so far
very Many people think that mobile
applications are something standing on the side of
the main system that this is something unimportant
some small piece
affects the security of only one
user yes what is some
a data mart for the backend, which is not only
displays data But in fact it is
everything is absolutely wrong Well, first of all, yes
the first myth is that there is only one
the user and his safety as we
we know that if your application is on
actually set to
100 devices
And it contains a vulnerability date
vulnerable and security
not a single user of all u suffers
who installed your application
respectively if possible
operate on one
person Yes, to one of your clients, then this
will extend to absolutely
all
Well, current mobile applications
develop very very fast
In my opinion faster than others
system and at the moment it is a separate
the world with its architecture with its
data with their service components
infrastructure and all other current
the power of mobile devices
run on mobile apps
inside mobile applications is huge
the number of calculations and according to its kind
its execution of mobile applications
a lot of data latitudes are saved
data is processed
perform some calculations
devices That is why they store in
quite a large amount
information that does not, for example, the same
the web itself is not a data mart and yet
one delusion with which we constantly
face yeah that's what stores
applications and so check
applications before publication and what
in principle, we have more security
nothing to do everything you need to do
to know this is that stores are also not like that
like Google Apple Huawei everyone else
pursue their own goals and
they check that you are not
use their private pi for what you
follow their rules, what is not there without
permissions do not try to reach out to
some
hardware stuff and so on and so on
That is, for the safety of your
app name objectively spit
Let's also do things that are often not
take Attention is what is mobile
application
may entail too
small damage to be covered
risks on the one hand probably yes But
on the other hand yes if it is an application
for example banking or if it is
some kind of application with a photo will be extremely
it's embarrassing if they steal from you
money or your private photos
correspondence agree
not so nice when you turn out to be a victim
it is you and not some mythical
Human
another misconception is that
mobile applications are very
narrow attack vector and very common for
in order to exploit
get compromised yourself first
device or pay him a physical
access
most of the vulnerabilities that we
consider today
it's not, it's the easiest way
receiving a compromised device
receipt also and after that already
getting all the application data there but
In fact
most vulnerabilities can be exploited
and was remotely or put in a nearby
application on the device
Well, the very last thing actually
What will today's report be based on?
is that the operating system is
protective properties, functions and its
the safety model will protect me
and my data from intruders Of course
no operating system also contains
vulnerabilities
and plus using the built-in tools
systems can be allowed to be simple
logical error or just something wrong
take into account and your data will be under
so it shouldn't be considered a threat.
mobile applications of some small
part of it is really important and
probably one of the main
applications your front which is running
first hostile to him environment on
user's device you do not
control everything that is inside
your application
the compiled files are in
banglah in resources in everything else everything
it becomes available immediately after
how users download your
application
in this please pay attention to
mobile phones Yes, this is one of the main channels
receiving your services by users and
its safety should be considered
a lot of attention And finally
let's start
main gist of the report
all the examples that I will give
met in real applications all
coincidences
random If you recognize someone don't
talk about it
All all vendors all manufacturers
applications in which we found
vulnerabilities have all been notified
notified don't know how it's right
say they got information about it
and I hope that it has already been fixed here Well, how
I already said it didn't work
All I wanted to cram into the timing but
let's try
and of course the most common
problem associated with the misconception about
that if the file is stored in a sandbox
then you do not need to encrypt it additionally
In it, the data is somehow protected
the operating system will do itself No
it's not that often, probably in the 90's
percent of the time we find something in
applications
inside the file system in a sandbox, or
vlogs or somewhere else usually this
the most dangerous What could be passwords
user logins pin codes
session id which by the way
live for a week
by month which received which you can
no problem logging into user account
bypassing any form of authentication
according to his session continue to work
this is a screenshot from one application which
Well, naturally kept sec ure Pin
secure and stored all data side by side
session and also login And whatever
it is connected It is natural not only with
Android iOS Approximately the same cookies
data please all that is necessary for
access to the application where else but
file system it can occur
Yes, of course, the cache is very few in
application disables network caching
requests
or forgets that in a number of requests
can be
may be information, especially if it
passed not in the body of the request A in
parameters
Ghetto So pay attention then
that cache is enabled by default
is usually done in order to
speed up the application
show what users while data
updated have the ability to applications
disable either the cache completely or
turn it off for some sensitive
requests so state developers
Yes if you listen to us know what to in
different operating systems in iOS
Android for some specific
queries that may contain
sensitive or confidential
user information is possible and necessary
disable cache if you don't want to
turn it off completely
next place where very often
problems are slipping these are the logs
applications it can be system logs
or logs that the application writes for
further sending it to the backend
very often, in fact, this is not a sin
self-written Code sins yes which we write
we And our libraries which we
connect
the world is the same only http Yes
connected in wrong configuration
can write given block im faced
with various libraries that
by default for some reason when connecting them
project very write messages with
confidential information to the system
block in the location is unfortunately not
cleans up pro gourdom
start up it retracts only
correct settings of those libraries
which you connect So if at
development of your project you connect
some third-party or look vlogs
look at what she writes there and
does it contain anything interesting
getting interesting data
which you can compromise
user safety
but for those who are looking for yes For those who
trying to parse the application there
own or others Yes, who starts what
you can try to search Well first
naturally any mention of standard
standard grep search there
words passport pin session and the rest yes
that is, any places where the application
can store data
apart from that so it's very extensive
search yes i.e. you will have a lot
you can search
specifically in meaning because you
know exactly what you are
did you set the pincloud
What is your name What login was displayed and
specifically by value, you can search where
this data is lit
Also
I recommend looking not only at clean
the value of Ho and on their derivatives
which are easy to turn back into
initial value is various functions
md56 b64 conversion
and everything else, that is, if you
meet
something
pin in md5 yes then with a large share
probabilities anyone who gets md5 yes
can can implement it back
just google first
Google value and First link
getting what you need
And of course, in addition to the application files
watch it on cache very rarely it
disconnected and very often found there
extremely interesting things That is, even if
you failed to unscrew the spinning in
application Yes and look at its traffic
can be viewed in the cache and with a large share
probabilities there will be all necessary
you network requests
the problem which is the derivative yes here
this
the next is the keys to services All of us
love to use different
libraries components services that
help us in our work Well, of course
there to write a conditional write a service yourself
maps are much more difficult
it makes no sense when there are ready-made solutions
which for some money you
supply
But
everything would be fine if the keys to these
services were not stored in the application
there are a number of legitimate absolutely keys
which should be in the application
client
Talking firebase like which
performs authentication
initial in
analytics system to send there
data A has keys that should not
get into the application
these are keys with great privileges
for example some server keys yes
or those that give access
which the developer provided
more additional control over e.g.
your account in there in VK or linkedini
if you have similar integration
our what we met yes specifically on
this slide shows the key from firebase
firebase Cloud messaging which
valid from several services that
represent google yes it is
statickmap Street View and so on like this
on and on and on and on yes that is having received
this key is implemented in your application with
small hacks you can here at your expense
getting services is not really
as scary as being able to send
random push messages
given key
with incorrect configuration when
it is a server key i.e.
the main ones that I wrote to you
firebase if you include in your
application and it will become known
he can send to the attacker
custom push notification to
absolutely all devices
on which your
free text application
pictures gifs
heading whatever it is he
can it do unlimited
number of times and all your users
get these pushes
a lot of companies
talking and talking do not consider
reputational risks because im not
Interesting
But how
great risk if all your
users will be notified with
call to come somewhere or leave
competitors Well, I think it's not very
it will be nice Why such situations
occur Yes for various reasons Well
first write out one key which
access to all services much easier
and faster than Write out 10 keys from 10
services and their right places
apply second it actually
as a rule, the complexity in the documentation before
difficulties in managing these keys that
also not very maybe not very
obviously plus a similar problem
arose during the relocation and merger
multiple services one when in
in principle, it is not clear the key to what
fits And that's automatic or in
principle checking the keys of which
you found in the app it's very
interesting thing Where can I look for them And
what to do next with them
naturally in resources during the application
file system yes that is that in
production work of our mobile phone
then you can look in the code
accessing certain well-known sdks
Yes which function gets the value and
look
do the keys glow there very often these
the keys glow already in the network
interaction between the mobile app and
sometimes they are not stored in the mobile phone but
server comes the value of the North
key there were several such cases in
traffic is also recommended to see Also
you can change the entropy analysis when
we get rows from
application from the file system and
analyze them for random
whether the sequence is
random or not and how likely yes these
random sequences can be
keys from various services further
By looking at the context, we can understand
what is this service go to the documentation
see how to check validity
key and potentially gain access
above the account there are several useful
resources that can help you
multiple repositories on github
that allow you to search for secrets and in
some of them have the possibility
automatically check the currency of these
secrets are not always this code is relevant here
so actually combining these
41 can help you in finding the secrets of not
only really mobile
applications, but in principle in all
the rest plus To some of them you can
add your own custom
checks custom validators and if u
you have any internal services
which your applications can handle
third-party applications yes Or in principle
any web service
some kind of unified unification of all
your applications, you can also
watch and write your own
plugin to determine what
your internal keys that are known
only you didnt leak somewhere outside
following derivative of unsafe
data storage is a local check
pin code
21st century 20 2023 and already this year
a few more applications that do
local verification of the pin code Why is this
do not understand but I have one
guess since mobile apps
develop
much faster than BC as a rule Yes
they are usually decoupled from the process
development
parts in principle of the main services Yes and
they can implement some chips
on the client if for example Back is not
supports short authentication or
how else can you do it
client Yes but
very often make mistakes when
it is the only thing that protects our
user and his account from
attackers principle from
unauthorized access is easy
some Activity or some
view with a password which is actually
does almost nothing
How to search and what to do
as usual checks the local pin code
we see a few things
saved in the application look at them
name in the code, look for where this name occurs
in one of the applications for example
Android app decompiled found
where we get the word Secure Pin
saw this function looked for where this
function is applied where it is
still called and found this one
wonderful
cat That's the one in the Unlock fragment takes
4 digits entered by the user and
compare it with the value that was
derived from
in fact, local verification of the pin code
that simply hides or destroys
our Activity and shows the interface
user
it is much easier when we have
Just
iq-value whose value
user and what we have saved
the code is fake but for some reason
this function did not get there and
find it very very easy
How to bypass local pin verification
it can be bypassed naturally with
various tools like
frieds
xpost and other things
replacing the return value of the function
comparisons
You can also change the decompiled
value in Smiley code in Android to
the check function always returned us
tru put this app and bypass and
if the application allows
make a local backup you can take
backup open it easy to replace
the value of the user's pin code to your own
there are four zeros to pack
back restore enter four zeros
and get into the application
and of course they can help
pokatul jadex for Android oh well
Frida in principle for Android and for iOS
and which will allow you to find and replace
the right value to get into
app without pin out of 10
manually analyzed applications in
last year we did not personally manage to get around
can pin code in seven applications
What else can we do if we are local
check the pin code
you can do it naturally
add biometrics it is logical that in all
applications have a biometric
authentication so convenient finger
looked at the phone got into the application
super But as a rule it happens that
on Android and on her own meter
implemented somehow wrong and get
in the application you can very easily
examples about android about
Yose And this is also a very common occurrence.
when biometrics is implemented incorrectly
why it is implemented incorrectly and what
this is where the biometric takes place
shading can be done
the right way, that is, you can
the basis of your fingerprint or there face
biometric data to access
secure storage
get the key from there that will allow
there decrypt the data decrypt it
and then do something with them
this is a function when we have our biometric
data is used to decrypt
gaining access to something there is a second
path that allows
also biometric identification but
in fact, we just ask the system A
there is such a finger in the system there conditionally
speaking or whether our biometric
the system tells us yes or no
naturally replacing the returned
true value is false because we have nothing
there is no need to do further we can
very easy to bypass the biometric
authentication and the second common mistake
which is also rare Who implements in
its applications is a reaction to
changing biometric data in
system That is, we have registered
one finger
which message we receive input
applications if we register a second
finger Yes for example how would I be an intruder
got there conditionally speaking phone
registered a second fingerprint there
I can use it to enter the application
Yes, this is also quite an interesting case.
That is, if your application is not
responds to biometric changes
user data and does not offer
re-authenticate
user confirmation then keep in
mind that adding the second
next prints either face completely
can be there without any manipulation with
some special tools
it's a matter of getting around surrenders it's one flag
when implementing the biometrics function
How is it possible in theory there more or less
it is correct to implement such an input before
like functionality in an app by
biometrics naturally is the easiest
option without any bells and whistles
additional protections, but nonetheless
user originally
log in to the API gets some
access tokens client clicks there
touch-sensor looks into the phone in from Thor
either from the Security include we get
key
conditional actually we refer to
stories
to encrypt data
the encrypted value is placed in some
vault fumbles prefs chain somewhere
that's all, that is, we are encrypted
the value on the key that is stored in
phone hardware storage which
protected by biometric access saved
token that gives access to the account
this approach is quite normal when we
you need to authenticate on the server
the user is prompted immediately
biometrics he puts a conditional finger
if he came up then we are also in
securiting Live or in case Tor
send a request for data decryption
which we received
if all is well there our geometric
data matched
hardware parts decrypt us
data returns the token that we
send to the server and otnify in
application is enough just nothing
local unencrypted is not stored
we use biometrics because
was not conceived as it was to accelerate
usually used and it is quite
more or less normal process
locations
biometric
the next interesting thing that we
managed to find this
safe
insecure flutters
flutter is a cross-platform language where
we write in Dart the language from Google and this
code can work like on android How
on iOS But there is one small
That
if with operating system inside
flutter as inside any
cross-platform language just
platform application
apply the plugin approach which
one side looks at the Dart code
for example crossplatform and the other
interacts with the system
turns out some bridge between
operating system features and
crossplat
language and
because the popularity of this kind
more and more and more applications
gaining momentum a lot
developers use
these plugins are freely available code
they can be studied and Yes, not all plugins like
turns out to be useful especially if they have
there is a word Secure
example of such wonderful code
is a Flutter Secure storage plugin
Despite the fact that he is a security on Android
it's actually pretty good
drawn kistora gets from there
the key encrypts the data and everything in general
more or less good, but in the case of soyos
he just takes the data that you give him
submit
text saves them for
yes kichi need secure vault yes she is
protected by the system but again ways
in order to get data
there are quite a few exceptions, that is
firstly it is the same instrumentation
apps via frida abjection and
other frameworks are
local encrypted backup to which
fall meaning the language of the chain is
cloud backups and bag sync
keys in iOS
all your devices in common
there are ways to do this and one more
an interesting nuance is that when you delete
applications again default file
the system is overwritten but the key data
remain and if not realized
self-removal of kitsch on there at
first start or grinding these
data by installing the application again
we will receive the same data within
that is, in fact Uda application Yes
we make certain
changes add the library there
conditionally
Frida Frida Agent we put it on
devices get access to and whose but to
to all its elements, therefore
yes it is not there very big
problem but still keep such
data like passwords pin codes and
most sensitive most sensitive
user data in plain text, even
in ketch
very very not recommended
If
the pin code that you currently see on the screen
used for local
PIN code authentication and For
further submitting it to the request
biometrics
what it actually does
plugin called Local auf local
authentication but I think here in principle
everything is clear even in the github there is an issue
that you can bypass Touch ID on this
plugin that is implemented incorrectly
But unfortunately
it is closed approximately with the wording that
then that it can be bypassed to enter
application
I don't understand what you are talking about
Tell me just more details or
or score in fact the author scored everything
scored and by the way it is built in if you
look at the link in the flutter package
local identification which
used in a lot of places
So if you are exploring flator
applications Look at the plugins that
connected there if there is a case with iOS
for example you can't do it there
Look at its version in Android like this
how they are extrapolated one code by
fact on two platforms
and if you see an application of either Secure
storage was about that with a large share
probabilities Well, in principle, if you
you see the PIN there in plain text or in
some
disguised they are not much then with very
most likely it is possible
bypass and access
user account without knowing it
password and without knowledge foam Well, in principle
good practice if you
use some plugins and their code
open Please see what they are
do and what What functionality
brings this to your application
actually about what he was talking about
previous speaker Yes but
it still concerns not even against
creatures Yes and not molvare
in principle, yes, how it is implemented
functionality you want to add to
to yourself in the application
very easy imperceptibly a lot of time but
saves you a lot of time later
further fixing problems with
security what else Yes of all this
but most of these vulnerabilities
it turned out you can operate without root
and without jailbreak the most various
backup methods neighboring
applications through various vulnerabilities
And of course, in the simplest way
still is a jailbreak yes but so
However, most of them can
exploit data get without it
sandbox app what's in ios what's in
Android will not protect your data If you
you dont think about them yourself and you yourself
additionally do not encrypt or
hide from the eyes of intruders
check what exactly you are connecting in
their plugins how the functionality is implemented
at least superficially, or if it
impossible to do so here is closed after
adding it and calling the functionality
see what ends up in your
the application how it behaves in
different situations
and what else can you tell yes And what else
I would like to light up in there in
future releases
more complex bugs Yes, but which also
quite common and
reveal a little more exactly how
you can get information about the application
app sandbox data
without tearing or
jailbreak is right Well first of all this
getting arbitrary files from
application sandboxes at least in
Android can be made two three
ways via content providers via
copying to cache through pastors versal
and so on In principle through the pastor
versal Yes, and through working with Zip archives
If your application implements
such things
then you can either do it or do it
arbitrary code in application context
replacing the source If your application
uses Here either in principle
overwrite any file inside the sandbox
applications Well and classically since
a lot of applications work with
webs and
uplinks type links i.e. look
to some standard application
at least 5-6 schemes registered
which they can open these Print when
We open
page in the browser and whether it shows
open it in the application and often in
parameters of these links are passed
various urls to bypass which
it's not that hard, literally
months ago
recommended developers to fix
URL which which was
that he was just checking for his
domain in the transmitted url, that is
relatively speaking domain com should
contained in the steering wheel which passed
user Well, of course, this is a test
very easy to get around we say we are
go to
evil.com/ment.com or a question mark there
some parameters any place
presence in Orel of this domain
allowed us to bypass the check and such
there are plenty of examples even if
leave out brackets
operating system vulnerabilities
which, in my opinion, is up to 6 or up to the seventh
Android very crookedly parsilo various
links to code giving the same values
displaying users coming to
completely different urls so I hope
that soon we will definitely
Let's talk more about these
vulnerabilities
subscribe to the channel i post
various Tula news
on mobile application security and
I hope that the materials will be available Yes
so a few useful things that
can help you with a fairly simple
application analysis Yes and search for that in
what are we talking about today
talked about what i said
really sorry that
still the most common
common problem is
insecure data storage It would seem
so much time has passed
you if about you on you in top ten
which for the weib he is there as if saying
every year progresses change
changing schemes
points
unite add something new
for mobile phones last update you Mobile
top tent was in
2016-2017 five years have passed so far
since all listed in you mobile
vulnerabilities actual
don't lose
its place in applications
mobile phones are becoming more and more
more and more for everyone
for every respected company there is
several external and a dozen internal
applications that help them
in daily work If
external applications somehow
internal applications are checked as
the rule contains a huge
number of different
attacker having received which he can
get
additional Attack vector on the company
on this I have everything thank you very much for
attention and will be happy to answer questions
respected viewers colleagues
thank you, thank you
very very much information
what was on the last slide Here but
I think that the next series will try but
Anton When he reported to us the quantity
their speakers at lexicops and immediately
realized that this is apparently two seasons
some story okay really
the first question in this at the end you started
talk about the fact that you fork was updated
dofiga for a long time I tested the squirrels of the year
three back and followed Diva
applications that now I want to join
mobile princesses what now
basically the same thing you take on
in fact, any application is popular
which you like
and you start to see how it works
what does she keep in herself what does she do in
actually the majority
vulnerabilities we found
they reported they were not within the framework of projects
you go some there Bought yourself a new one
SIM card needs to put a personal application
Cabinet set such an interesting that
it is stored there and you start watching it
So periodically you find very
interesting things that are not there
should Well, if you say that this one is straight
now you want to pour as you said
a lot of cross-platform now very
a lot of flutter is getting bigger and
more
less cord reaction but still
they are present now on horse flator
And
application made on it in principle
tools to analyze
There are quite a few of them here is such a moment
the same problems with what to find a woman
the application is quite simple but complicated
be an intruder who this jar
expedited some opinion of that
as far as the user platform such
hackers who find the ultrasound platform
operating system Well, yes, like Android
operating room operating room
she has a standard system there
role models of the standard model
security that protects the sandbox
No one but your application can
get data from this sandbox
conditionally there is access there somehow further
security use it access to
sensors to receive privacy there
all emaf MC others that's all
it's all possible it's in
most cases can be bypassed either
find or find the application itself
which will allow you to read the file here
or
this is more about android because
not a very big problem in a big
fragmentation
Do you have classic google pi
the perfect example of Androids and there is how
a huge number of manufacturers
who shovel Android for themselves Android
in this regard, Google is trying
there they did tamp everyone
a fairly large number of steps to
to this they are now supplying a vigorous
Android functionality separately Security
patches are rolled through Google Play Yes
but as we know now not at all
devices have Google Playstation
Huawei is unclear how they will pay for the patch
Google which comes through the standard
application update mechanism here
Android tries to do but still
we see quite a lot
quantity
devices that
like to pull up Android itself if you take
for example the same Samsung then
last year one of the serders found
where is samsung
Google system app for that
so that I can understand some
Samsung functionality was needed
leaving there an amusing flag which
was called Bypass Security That's sending
Specially formed intent for
a link to the application and with this flag
established vturu
system application downloaded from the link
you need and installed it did it
device administrator and deleted all
other applications
found this BUG didn't tweet it
it was a very very interesting thing
rely on system security if
you make an app okay
I have a question like this from real life
they told me, but because
listened to a person not very competent in
it just happened to be a scam
mobile banking app I want
understand if this is even possible
and if so, what was there at all
place to be means how it happened
standard all call from service
bank security But what was
remarkable they In support of their
legitimacy
to the banking application on my
a friend was sent a push with some
text and he began to trust them after
this and lost some part of all
means What is it Who is it really
it looks very similar at least
telling Yes it is the possibility of sending
ears if
Appendix Yes contains as a rule
notifications Yes, no one writes their own
services use Google either
some alternative stuff
usually
if the application of this bank had a key with
wrong privileges
it can be sent
either on a specific device or on
device group or all devices
there depending on the parameters like this
way we could well send a push
message either to this user soon
just simple
sent to everyone Here And thereby Let
what is remarkable is that you trust
this message came from legitimate
applications that's what sent you it
how would the attackers yes using
key
free text is five lines per
nutrition
uses It's standard just
improvisation of standard functionality
fully
This is a very good way to make
user trust
let's say yes to a mobile attacker
Cool But from practice, here's some
some memorable occasion
maybe or maybe the most funny
memorable occasions I often
I'm actually telling the details.
I will paint the bottom line is that
exploitation of the vulnerability on the system became
possible only thanks to
bundle
lack
in tank fix session and mobile
application which
took itself parameters and sent them
further and that's it
together
getting the session id there on
bike by sending a mobile app
to be able to use it
get full access to your account
user
once again proves
shows that even a small
flaw
which is unclear as yet about
exploit can quite become
one of
vectors of one of the nodes
in the attack vector
seriously what's up wait question from
chat How to check Is it possible with a key
farms send let's go
if there are links Here But if possible
will send
That
information
send here But in principle
there is a search article about a person
who earned about 100 thousand
dollars
analyzing a certain number
applications from Tor
Based on the article, you can check it
I suggest you choose
categories and emojis that are currently
will appear on the screen
[music]
Come on Truth or myth Come on what
with the latest it
Our first speaker
five years
why not
no it is
only works to defeat no there
there are many one way
ok super let us please
matrix One more time so let's go
from the first batch
Oh God why and explain just how
here from the first batch
because it is very
abbreviation
i really don't know that's why
I can only guess three different
number for abbreviation therefore such
writes Well yes it's actually 8 letters
between the letter C A and therefore Also
not bad therefore
any word
ok thank you thank you very much
and we are slowly moving to the median
moving on to our next speaker
often Danila Kokorina will say about
introduction
and about how to create secure software
Hi all
Hello everyone, my name is Danil Kokorin and I
web developer from the custom team
Jet info system development
and now I will tell you about the introduction
web development and how to create
safe by
first let's get to know each other
I will tell you what we can do and what is included in
our duty is basically we
we do digital development
Specifically, this mobile application
portals to applications and external sites
So what are we going to talk about today?
are these web vulnerabilities and what are they linking
represent now there will be only three
vulnerabilities are basic For more
visibility also leads the top 10 about you
vulnerabilities further you can
familiarize yourself with them
and see what they are
provide more specific
and the second is how to write a secure
share our experience what we use
in development and what is needed or
recommended use for you
The first is vulnerabilities
websites and web application are available to everyone
even scammers and hackers, and if on
the site has a place where you can lead
some information upload photo file
or
to convey some information
in the form of a message, an attacker can
use this place for a hole in your
application
as i said earlier we write projects and
questions
our security is particularly critical
because we have to transfer to the customer
finished product
in general, any programmer is above graduation
Junior must know At least three
minimum vulnerability To understand with
how it works what needs to be addressed
attention So the time has finally come
talk about vulnerabilities and see
what they represent
the first vulnerability is the warp action
this vulnerability that interacts with
database if your site
interacts with the database
maybe your site is vulnerable to this
vulnerabilities
as we see from the picture
something injects or from the name of the injection
so it introduces malicious code using the example we
see
on the example We see that we have a field
to search for products by ID and in this field
any user can enter and find
any product this field refers to
us to the database and issues back
goods But if you lead there not like her
implies itself
search string And the code is just
will take and delete the table as it can be seen
For example
now let's move on to the interactive example
here we see how a hacker comes to us
to the site and enters an additional line
to submit for registration
registered on registered special
value
and he is given admin rights, that is, us
this place was not protected and he was able to
register as admin
and goals as I said earlier the main goal
this is a database But what can you do with it
do and I'll tell Although it can delete
steal data or replace data in
for any purpose
and now a couple of interesting cases
over 8 million user data
freepic were stolen using SQL
injection or hackers attacked
web interface of Stream devices using
escalenge to use them for
dudosatak
now let's analyze the attack in the code. We see
that we have a request to receive
what city what city
for example Moscow St. Petersburg but if there
enter not a city, but some command
as we see the user here it is
converted into a team and
is recorded as commands are executed
but how is it to defend to the rescue
comes escaping escaping it
replacing dangerous characters with safe ones
to
our server was unable to read this data
and replace them with safer ones
here we see again the same example this
request for data but only already
For example, PHP has a built-in function
for escaping it takes this function
converts to safe input and already
writes the database without any
problems
after we talked like this
protect Let's move on to the next
attack is xcss is change at which
hacker injects some kind of script directly to us
to the site and infects our site this place
interesting fact that half of all sites
or to be more precise, more than 60 percent
vulnerable to this attack today us
known
three main attacks now I get you
let's talk now let's talk about each of
them more But in fact this
the list is very conditional and constantly
updated, that is, attacks on the house were
relevant That's just this five-year period
now we see how the user enters
some data This is the type we have
instant
instantly this page you
apply returns custom
fragment
attacker injects malicious script
and at the end we see the URL with the code
this link
we see the attacked site search on the site
malicious script
the attacker's website and this
I will tell the user in more detail what
it's happening here
in the search for sites put the script for Translation
to another page and theft of the cube that is
data for user authorization
taken to another page and stolen data
and further stored from the name it is clear
that this vulnerability is stored somewhere A
if it is stored, then we have it
we show directly on the site the places can
be completely different it can be
forums comments and the like
That is, now users lead
data and send them i will not be saved
right in the comments
all users entered before it appeared
some code that he wrote in advance
and the last subtype for today is on
interface elements
by changing interface elements we can
change some picture
demonstration Similarly, we can
cause some error or
hovering the mouse is not essential
that your code worked
this is actually a very interesting attack
because it is important for a potential hacker
have social engineering skills
to
carry out this attack That is, he must
understand how it interacts
site user What to look for
attention and goals is to either steal
account or admin or user
or transfer to a malicious page
now also let's talk about cases
May 29 to 31 there was a surge
Malicious Attacks on WordPress Sites
more than 130 million and this was done in
this period and also not without
of our domestic site is the site
public services it has a malicious script where
advertisement was shown
and now let's talk about shielding
shielding in this case as well as
SQL only now it's on the client
let's analyze approximately the client, we see how
there is a user input and we
protect for me this is a dangerous symbol
on the left to safe characters it's on the right and
we get back safe
custom that's what does not give
triggering this script
the next attack we have is a fake between
site requests or CRF This is a type of attack
to a site that is produced using
fraudulent site or script that
forces the browser user
fulfill
desired actions
on a trusted site where
user is authorized authorized But
how it works
the request comes from, for example, an infected site
And on our main site there is already
given authorization e.g. data
these cookies can be authorizations
cookies are sent along with the request when
every user action
then let's look at an example of how it works
imagine the site mail.ru and that the hacker
made a mirror site mail1.ru
the user visits mail.1 and
enters some request there and sends
it on the main
to the main site this site has
such a mold in the mirror and a request for
main due to the fact that the user is already
authorized on the main site
The main site sends the request because
think that
user can be trusted and request
is correct
and here everything is the same as attacks
the main targets are users either
site administrators
here It is important for a hacker to either steal data
or, for example, make a translation on behalf of
this user
and very striking cases are
aerospace company
companies in 2000 stole more than 42
million dollars from advertising or
hackers stole the data of more than 65 thousand
Japanese company website users
coyotecma developer developer
now let's talk about protection
in this case protection in this case protection
is the use
freeworks which are embedded
attica with RF tokens
and such tokens are
tracking each time request and here
this data That is, every time
a unique token is generated so as not to
steal it and such figurines is
But if you use no then you can
use any other freeworking
and what we had to face wrote
project for
automobile companies that collected
applications for
users and this site in general
publicly available everywhere That is, everyone
a person can log in and send data
But what if the user wants
send not data but already some
command to hit you database or else
another example
application for a contract online on a card
loyalty It's generally just a gift for
hacker a lot of fields, that is, these are all
places are vulnerable all these places need
work out
and fix it like this
You talked about vulnerabilities at the very
there are a lot of them and
like i said on you top 10 collects
basic but it's time to talk like
make it so
the developer wrote already protected code not
leaves security holes
actually this process is very easy
automate
Let me tell you more
it all starts with
When we don't even have any
project must first be assembled
learning materials and share with
each new employee or who have
we already have and the second stage is to create
certain database so-called
a check that will come to everyone's mind
to the developer when updating For example,
we have a vulnerability list of mine there
store developers learned some more
vulnerability and add to this knowledge base
now let's talk about the stages of development
one of the most important parts in
our situation because
developers actually have enough
easy to implement
certain screws so they are on stage
developments could check some
details
check some details and look after
vulnerabilities
and the first step is chicap like me and
previously said users more precisely
developers can come in and watch
what is wrong, that is, the project is launched, we
Familiarize yourself with what tools are
a good decision what tools
bad and can also be cleaned or
add At this stage of the tool and
now let's talk about these tools
At this stage, there will be more
front-end analyzers some of course
fit either kent i talk about it a bit
I'll tell you later, but I personally use
these three are easy enough
to write and talk about the first
currently unimaginable
a project without a screw, but not everyone knows
that also synth has a plugin
Security is a very popular app.
a very popular plugin uses it
more than 550 thousand users per week and
this plugin helps to write customization
one and use it in different places
Let me show you how
works, there is such a code that
wrote the developer and dedicated this
this is a weak point and now he knows what
gotta work on it
Correct mistake
second
if we don't have
special settings we can
use
additional directly in the application for
writing code and such an example is
sonor lind this app fits
not only for frontend languages but also
either Kent
how it works we see that
the developer writes some code to him immediately
highlight the problem
wavy lines and he can do it too
to correct
Now let's talk about packages
which we use daily
practically impossible at the moment.
generally submit no project to
view of the site without packages But not everything is on
actually know what packages can be
vulnerable i for example the budget of this is not
knew and
how to solve impossible
all need to know some need some
the automation package is
retridgs it can be downloaded directly from
Google Chrome
and it will automatically highlight
vulnerabilities as we see in the example
the developer went to the site immediately
vulnerable version is highlighted
jquery libraries and it shows what is not
So
And when the developer has accumulated
enough changes he makes push in
our guide conditional version control system
and at this stage there is also lint
checks
our code per frequency but in this step also
you can build security to manual
not manual automation, but some
the application has completely collected this
application and automated
tested it with this app
is sast by example we see how
our code was scanned
passed paypeline but on the system
it fell and two errors are highlighted
now let's talk about testing one
of the most important parts in general in any
development for each large team on
currently there is a testing department
to find bugs what to check all
process but in our business it is also important
for someone else to check Security
and it's great for testers at
they should have their own security audit
they have to check for standards
security do pentesting do
vulnerability assessment and of course stress
testing or imitation dosa so that
There is
independent people to develop
take a look and decide what
we are missing
to that
come to an end now you know what
there are vulnerabilities that they assume
represent and how to solve the situation on
write less during development
let's say a cat with holes
[music]
thank you, thank you
I belong here
please tell me browser through
which users of these applications
enjoy if application somehow
vulnerable then the browser can protect it Yes
for example, the browser often protects us from
transfer to other people's and third-party
left sites you probably saw it but
the browser most often accepts this code
How
clean coin let's say it's okay to
it applies therefore the user needs
also treat it with a certain
caution, for example, add there
tabs where he is authorized like me before
said that there is an authorization vulnerability
either
keep a close eye on cleanliness
site where they go and so on browser
does not always protect but it is some
manipulations to do with it That is
the browser may not know this from the transitions
fog redirect
show the icon that they themselves work
approximately shows where else on the site
turn off security, he sometimes doesnt even
lets in general on these sites that is
browser browser doing something but not
completely understandable
what the user can do Well except
how not to cross
general transition By links is
probably the most important thing in hygiene
security, that is, it is necessary all the time
look at which link we are following Well
and, of course, the main task is
change passwords see what it looks like there
site I have a lot of my friends who e
went to a mirror site and paid
it turned out that is most often
work for user Well from base
data Of course, this is the main goal
this user, that is, makes some
phishing site like yes yes like me
said mirrors are made there literally
change one letter and immediately becomes
it is clear that well, the user seems to be
thinks this is the main site actually it is
mirror like your data is not there
gets anywhere enters data there on
in fact, a huge number
user experience from
data theft prior to transfer to the site i.e.
was even looking to do something on the main
the site can, that is, a lot
all you need to follow here are direct links
this is top 1
maybe eat
please Bye So maybe some
plugin that will do
security user experience one
I didn't really see that
Seems
but I wonder why, probably because
it is impossible to collect all sites together
you need to be able to, and I know how much
I had acquaintances That's all they start
think about it only when they are caught
that is, before that, no one has anything there for me
one password for 1000 accounts And when they
hacked Everything now I have 10 there
passwords I don't have them every day of the week
Therefore, yes it is Well, here are the main tasks
username is password if links in
house-2 returning with the browser uh They are the same
just passwords can store in themselves Yes
but it seems to be protected i.e. uh
you can steal it, but it's more like a site
through
code but not from this storage
passwords, that is, passwords that are in
browser as far as I know they are protected
but no it's not 100%
years I think 15 which in general
my school days in the browser
The opera was just beginning and there
it created just a text file somewhere
in my system deep
just these all these passwords were stored
file Well yes was thought about security
so I see the chat question
primary responsibility to protect
applications for funds
I don't know who wrote this
in general, of course, lies with the programmer
that is
the programmer is the most important thing in this
situations
the most important are to blame and that's it
I see controversy all the time but it's understandable
initially this is a backender. That is, they have
there is a call to the database call
there, well, that is, they do everything on the side
frontender servers send But
[music]
one layer will not do much will not eat
a lot of labor therefore
frontasia should know too Well here I am
for example, I talked with many people there a couple
they know everything and that's why it's very good
topic for fronts to talk about what
Security is one of the
the main tasks for me, even by the way, too
asked for an interview
vulnerabilities Therefore, I will say that yes, and that and
another wine is guilty
some frameworks that help
developers to write code more safely, or
out of the box has some settings
security For example
I know that Vue is used there
interpolation is protected, but if we
use HTML directives, then it is no longer
protected It is directly written by them
documentation that this is vulnerable react
vulnerable initially That is, he has a very
open cat he interacts with everyone
Therefore, in reaction, she especially thinks
need security Well and angular like me
he viet is protected enough
young My topic is just some kind of meme and
save
this is the situation when on Friday we
put everything on prod and everyone went home
and that's the head of this telling them lida what
do
to be honest it's more like yes when
My hand was lying here
after sleeping in the afternoon you get up here
such a situation
with a parrot
who was before me will be after So
could only chat there
how we all gathered here with the topic
security, I'll say yes
Dima flights took technical
directors
[music]
this question
Let's go, well, and here I can only
hope that Anton told the truth
and yes this event was in 2009
actually was the first divops Days
held so it turns out
community in order for the new to him already
over 10 years ok thank you very much
we as far as i remember another break i
I will interrogate you and ask him the most
stupid questions i have
Thanks for the class
What do you think awaits you
I think I'm on a tour of questions Yes
so let's first tell you how
you hit the dufficops we'll start with that
like who Pasha Introduce yourself and my name is
I'll talk camera Tinkov I'm an expert
group where all the components of the Jet system i
was engaged at all came from you can say
paper security
at the very beginning of my career, I was engaged in
with all this domestic compliance
personal data any diss
some sort of adjustment to that
or other regulatory document later
it somehow became to me under November
bother because well somehow it was
Boring and nothing new
basically everything that could be done
probably could have done the first couple
years I spent four years there
feeling not 4 years of experience of four
repetitions of one year
remained at work for the second year
Well, as if yes, and now I changed jobs
I came as I say, I can do this
but I don't want to give something else
time to learn and in general then I
did everything related to pikiai
everything related to multifactor Kai on
nosification Well, any normative here
mating with peak I'm in Russia it's still not
Seems like
it was also very interesting
in the end when all this was done
when the pandemic happened and everyone abruptly
Required remote access for protection
remote access Well, as it were, everywhere
it was very interesting
then Well, I'm generally in some kind of devos
something else when dealing with personas
tried to do something about it, but
somehow there were not enough skills to
get a job somewhere right away
do it yourself
The outlook may also be lacking
to find something and somehow in the end
managed to make such an internal
transfer in the company and first i when
still working on projects
some small tasks threw a podso
there, for example, I dont know in some system
container protection for example
cut users or policies
some kind of cover I'm already forced here
sat dealing with
before it works like this
arranged that the manuals are some kind of guides
Turned on turned off tested Well, in general
smoothly sink Well and now Later
some time of such work already
officially accepted into the family well
wait, that is, as if there are two
option either you found got it or doso
found itself which one is yours
I think I found ok
then let's move on to our own
questions What is the difference between containerization
from virtualization, well, they are generally often
compare that one another like me
it seems difficult to compare at all
some kind of implant to your outside
looks similar at all basic Difference in
that the container uses the kernel
operating system on which it
used e.g. don't know is
container built in Linux its easy
can be ported to other linux it's there
will work well there subject to availability for
running containers
with container Exotic will now be
compiled in Windows under Windows such
I have only seen such
all sorts of training tests and stands
maybe someone actually has
for example, they cannot be transferred
run on linux and vice versa i.e.
container containers it's isolated
operating system processor therefore
it uses the kernel then operating
system that works
virtual machine but it doesn't have any
values It can run where
anything in any conditions, as long as it was
corresponding correct hypervisor
which Windows works to move or
in something else there
In general, the main thing is the core and degree
humidity
Yes
I hope that Pasha did not get very far
from the main question Okay further how
build docker image to build docker
image need another docker image
get zero patient zero
patient zero
patient zero is called baseline
way, as a rule, of course, you can
make your own for this tool
but 99 percent of images are based on
some ready-made basic images
trusted trusted ones who are there
there is nothing superfluous, just some
the most key component is taken
the base image is created by the so-called
docker file that commands are appended to
for docker put this file put
I'll do dependency libraries there tomorrow
New image like this like this like this
it turns out
well imagine that the team
promotes
Why do they need another specialist Well, by the way Maybe
i just need a case in oil if it is
some application that I don't know
calculator which is five people
the team there also downloads and saws it
I don't know of the two
hiring a security guard may not be very
it is necessary if these are some bigger guys
which are already more
interaction of some processes
lined up then
Still, some damage is possible from
vulnerabilities
in short it would make sense to hire
some kind of security guard to introduce a role at all
some information security
or to save money you can give
safety in general it's all about scale
and probably, as always, in money and in
risks and loved ones
How does it affect at all Does this one affect
process
during app update
application development
Knyazev will include a report about this
security can if poorly configured
it can slow down and complicate
life if it is well integrated into
the process will only get better for everyone
because the time of the antics will still be
less and at the same time the quality of the code will be
it's better anyway
additional testing stage
testing It's all about how we do it
testing is introduced if it is some
application system
Return to elimination of all tricks
and technical tasks Probably it will be
long and effective if it is some
invisible to the developer
as inconspicuous as possible
security integration possible
generally great developers write code
mind their own business and don't get distracted
security is
ok yeah that's fair actually
question What is sit
is short for continent Delivery
or it happens that the Continent diplomant
it's such a combination
this approach of writing code in children with
with these branches by their merging
the final product if very briefly
sit superficially it's about
automation and about regular posting
new builds new releases here
This approach is technically implemented through
systems that are actually the core of these
all automation is they take code
they collect they follow the branches they
well I understand
docker is a launcher
containers cubernetis is a tool for
management
dockers Although now this is not entirely true
because fabernets is already dockerized
can't manage but can manage
other things that run docker
containers in short when you have
many applications in containers which
need network balancing need failover
stability there distribution of loads
dynamic and so on then you need
which will be these separate
Let's leave brokers to manage And
maintain such a productive
application functioning
so good for example here I am
lifted two whole containers of them to me
straight spinning can be considered that I understood
from where Well almost almost not enough 5 more
binary
here in general
just a little more to add a few
controllers
How it differs from secure development
secure development is part of the DSO is
such a big topic in which there is
infrastructure security security
development including there codes and
other things, here's what if you take Dixie
copies separately
the flex will be right there
secure development including
small piece accepted How to start
at all
we definitely have listeners who
want to maybe chat you will
You recommended to start
I would recommend starting with general
some knowledge in
linux security and networking here
I think
Know programming
here It depends on which side to enter if
in general, where everything Cox is probably possible or
from the side of infrastructure or from the side
developing it
another is needed just if the parties
infrastructure more focus on
all boxing turns out And if from the side
development, then this is where everyone
security codes probably on the second
focused because
And yes, of course, if you do
code security and secure
development, you need to be able to
uh uh that's where it's easier to start a career
Here come on so if we consider
precisely because the area
where is it easier if like I'm such a student
I have worked in what should I do next if
i want coke
be friends with IT people but also
administration of Linux networks And if
about code safety
be able to develop at least a little
understand that there I dont know static
the scanner spat out and
understand it's grooves okay okay
good I also saw that it was very
we have a marine theme there
studios have boats why where are you from
I think it's Docker
because he was himself Well, not really
first but he was the most popular this
means of congenization and since there
like a docker, these are the containers that
sea for containers is generally
logo of China then around this it all started
as the snowball gather in
gubernatis all at the helm on the logo
there seems to be a squid, but something like that
in general, all these about container things
they are with a nautical theme because of Docker
Well, that is, as if someone just pushed
ball and then the community just picked it up
and all yes yes like we are here we are about this
technology so we also slightly
such nautical ok i got mine here
the questions are over
I just don't know how to get a job
about what exactly about where why to whom i
I know that for example we have to live
spring ji zikers
at first it opens and as an option
careers can be considered this
opportunity either I think now
just some kind of huge lack of lack
shortfall shortfall
these professionals and the whole career can be
A lot of those
tell because when we
prepared for the stage I think it was straight
a lot of different people who
could be implemented
Well do it do it
I propose to welcome the next
speaker ok okay come on okay come on
come to the next speaker next
our speaker is Dmitry Evdokimov
talk about the classification
systematization of security measures
for compromise
Hello everyone, my name is Dmitry Evdokimov
And today I will tell you directly
about container security and cubernatis
I am the founder of technical
director of lantry company and our
team specializes in
containment safety and
cubernatis registrars directly
We are direct Only this topic is dealt with and
we develop our product solution and
Now let's dive into this a little
the topic is deeper at first small
disclaimer in principle in 40 minutes
It's hard enough
tell the whole topic
cubernets security and containerization
because the theme is really very
extensive but I will try to do so
so that at least those means of protection that
you must be used by me
opinion in the cluster I directly
I will tell you one of my goals
I bet you if you're not good
familiar with the safety of the Cuban and
containers then you could hold
some parallels are their usual
practice When you were doing well
Linux Windows network security
workstations and the like
while we focus on you
directly to
cubernets installations that cost
you inside it straight and we won't
capture cloud installations because
that they have some specificity Although
most of the moments that I am today
tell will be applicable to management
cluster
at the same time, I will not purposefully
to name some specific solutions
to be as objective as possible and you
directly during construction
security at home in the company could
I don't know when communicating with vendors
directly just a matter of election
different there between open source projects
ask the right questions and problems
it is right for you to choose one or the other
approach this or that directly
Here is the solution Well, of course all the same
direct knowledge is required
is container and what is kuberete
because in the report itself I have these moments
I won't reveal too much
Jenda big enough today how are you
you see a lot of points that
we have to consider with you
but again, that's not all Yes But
directly is the most important thing to me
sight
Well, let's start small first.
keeping that we as a specialist
security Until recently, very
accustomed to working with a very wide
a range of different security features
there start all sorts of Firewall of deaths
FPS hips Simonov
similar projects and many have immediately
the same question, how now this is our
knowledge to land directly on
containerized environment
launched in the same directly to
governor can we take it and
reuse or need some
changes or even need to take
products of another class Yes, today
directly with this I will try to you
and help sort out
certain parallels If you
understand these defenses
Where and how can you see them?
directly within the
cubernetics here while preparing
this report I thought how
directly approach this whole
classification systematization because
can be looked at very differently
protective equipment can be viewed
directly in terms of stage
offer lifecycle starting there
developing it directly
distribution of diplomats, as it were, one
approach and from one angle we will look
at the same time, regarding the same governorate
begins to participate only with us on
stages of the diploiran half Yes on the rest
stages of self-cubernation us in fact even
not yet present can be viewed with
using the classic four 4c Cloud
cluster container code This is already us
it's getting a little closer so
that those entities appear here
which we will talk about today and
clusters container and some code and
can be approached from the point of view
directly the places that it offers
various classes of protective equipment
identification protection response recovery
and you can add more
a moment that the place itself lacks
This is directly Deception deception
So I decided anyway
it's a little bit to approach but keep in mind
When you begin to consider any
means of protection You must also look at
what immediate life stage
application it is used which part
your infrastructure applies and what it is
task directly helps you
decide first moment what we start before
how even how some
Kubina from the cluster in general Yes, you need
understand And how we approach with
organizational point of view
to what can be used And how we
we will install it directly
cubernatis itself out of the box is not
is multitanate, that is, it
does not imply that there
many teams will live at the same time
many projects and so on
An analogy can be drawn If you have
some test systems
staging selling systems right there we
should also take care of the moment and how
we will directly lodge teams
and their application projects into a cluster
the Cuban is right here
Different approaches you can highlight and
as separate clusters for each
command this cool director will be able
select there several Control plain of
for one date play on this one
cluster to lodge a set of commands then
You will need to arrange a service Yes and
can also be used directly
When in each team specific
nodes directly
and the data to run their load can be
say that the last approach is calm
gets along with the rest, while you can
and can be combined
clusters simultaneously use All
depends on the amount of resources
that you use in the company
here is the next moment when we set
cluster even directly to itself
cubernatis is also engaged with us
registering the container after all
certain users usually
highly prelegated should
contact him directly and
them directly work well here
enough everything as if to say ordinary
need directly and am-sim system
pam system for control of both detachable
users but in a good way you have
should be very good
limited list of people who can
go directly contact
to the governorate right here from the point of view
user authentication you will have to
choose one or another identity provider
If you live in a closed circuit, this
maybe some internal
adventist provider there don't know
sharpened on your same asset director
Yes, if you live somewhere in the clouds
maybe directly but publicly
from some cloud provider
same you can use this
regarding permissions in ubernatu itself
there are quite a few different
authorization mechanisms but we have here
are also interested in the rights that we
we single out directly our
microservice issues to our users
This is directly r tank here and here
either periodicity and
check permissions yes or
directly at the diploma stage because
that in themselves these are the rights when
we issue to the service account per user
either per group connected through fossae through
roles and roll bindings are therefore very important
so that all rights that you grant in your
the system was consistent with the principles
you did not grant the least privileges
no dangerous rights that can be
through which you can raise privileges
log into the system or
access directly to
official information, that's why you need
tools from by analogy with social
segmentational of duties that checks
the fact that all rights are granted according to the principle
fewer privileges and enough
as I said, everything that we have in
kubernete is essentially apples and we have
there is a great opportunity here
This is directly check Yes itself
by itself, the cubernets system we have
declarative and that's all the resources go through
through this chain that is shown in
us on the slide and in this chain We are in
Basically, we can do whatever we want.
most security solutions
which are intended for the governorate as
since we use these opportunities
we can any yavlik at the stage of his diploma with
mutate something add something
to enrich something to exclude is undesirable
that we don't fit our there without
practices and so on we can just
on the contrary, check for compliance
which is completely and correctly developers
all configured applied and so on if
it does not pass our requirements then we
we can just in audit mode about it
warn either in mode
prevent such a
directly Yamal resource Yes
microservice in particular to run in
our cabin cluster and some
solutions there is a possibility even on this
stage something automatically add more
some resource directly
generate here analogies with others
systems are difficult to conduct because it
just the specifics of a declarative nature
kubernetis yes And for that they have
own developed inside
the mechanisms that are just based
on admission controllers today
day among all the decisions that I
met let's say the world can them
divided by those who are embedded in themselves
cubernetis and which are some
hinged class yes built-in possible
consider the Security policy which is already with
version 1.25 remote If you only
start your journey here safety
most likely you are not even with him
face never here to replace him
came under Security admission
controller Yes, this is a replacement for Security
policy of both of them the specifics is
that they will let you check
only directly to the resource where
start microservices all the rest
resources they are not capable of directly
watch A with version 1.26 in our
the governorate has a validation mechanism
his policy then he already lets us in
principle to check any resources exactly
for validation, not only under but also
for example some services diplomas
crane joe will
wei and any custom resources within
Internet here also on this chain so
how it is implemented these mutations
validation with webhooks We can
write your own admin
the controller is actively using
I don't know most of the solutions
systems for working with secrets solutions for
work service with mice and many others
operators Here and here is the last class
It's Direct Pole Engine
which are in order now five exist
it's right for me Must have which thing
she must be just on herself
directly takes on the task to a
mutate validate or something
generate according to
policies that you write and
apply you do not need to register
milestone and beyond that you don't need
directly add something else
just write directly
only a politician who is essentially also
is a clear-cut and further she will be herself
you can control it so that you
cluster appeared
here directly
logging all resources all holes that
pass directly through us
this chain also these actions can be
log directly in order to
to use this information in
further to investigate the incident and
in the province We have such
we have a direct mechanism
cubernets of dutlook it's the default
turn it off you need to turn it on here
need to look for something else
additional source of information
the main thing is to set it up, and for this you
you will need to write your own
auditorium in which it will be written
What resources At what level
detailing you want to use Yes and
in the future already either vlog just this
is written or sent to some Yes and
in the future, classical means again
security come to the rescue here
or some specific solution of course
already use this information and there
checks for specific signatures Either
we send it all we are at the siem level
there is a different correlation of this
information and so on, that's why this
some extra part of the policy
Engine control Yes, they can
do prevent cubernet-lock it
the task is simply to log everything
operations at the level at which we
directly want next after
how we directly deployed something
to our cluster yes it can be
microservice the same podik it will be
use the image We need
check
compliance with various
signs yes to match there the best
practices so that it does not contain
certain known vulnerabilities
malicious code or any
the secrets that I have named here
sensitive information or
the correctness of the signature of the image itself Here
it is very important how can this be
implement directly
First, these scanners can be divided into
two classes of checks This is directly
static checks that do not require
launch image and this image can
download or serve anywhere
analysis either dynamic for that
have to download the image
some directly throughout the
separate cubernets cluster which
can play some role
there is a son of boxing Yes, for example, he will
directly check it here as
you understand if you draw analogies
by classical means, these are
containerized compositions and dastas
which at the entrance we already receive not
Source code Yes and directly
receives ready-made images as input and
tries them via launch either
static parse and give
information And where is a similar class
solutions can be directly with us
built in they can be built in all
sit yes
thus, at the assembly stage Absolutely
transparently for the developer, we can
be a securitype line where after
our image is already assembled, we can
analyze on verification which
were on the slide above, at the same time you need
keep in mind that not all images
are collected from your source code
somehow you can use
ready for the database to queue and
there are some others like that
system components you already have them
use as they are
images of the study they rather have you
does not appear but we can
directly referring to the match
management with some periodicity Yes
for example, the frequency of updating the database
known vulnerabilities go there
and collect information
O
those images that we did not scan
for example in the process
directly during the diploma again
we remember those stages of mutai tires and
adminish and validation adminshin controller B
this moment we can also watch and
checking any of these properties is simple
running your specific
cubernet controller which will also
download the image, check it and issue it
verdict Maybe this is our microservice
run now in the environment or not
well, the last one directly
The final stage is runtime yes here
it turns out the application we already have an image
works in cubernetics cluster Yes and that
we already have it anyway
started here and we can here
check we analyzed before when
we analyzed it, but at the same time this
stage is convenient to use in what plan
that we are sure that this
the image we use and works
because you're sitting on stage 3 yes there
so can developers out there
tens of hundreds to produce A to real
production but just a few will reach and
no sense them constantly perry
scan because it's just well
just a waste of time and
resources are more profitable and more efficient
skip and always be in
course on the state of security of those images
who us really using and
runtime information just to us about this and
it helps that we are sure that we have those
images that are used therefore more often
of all Perry I scan those images that
work in welts they just lie
somewhere bridgestar because maybe
copies lie used of which
only the latest
Okay, our micro service passed the checks we
he was allowed to start What else can
in terms of security here
Directly add this
directly managing secrets
secrets are everywhere this is not a prefix
some kind of containers it could be
some tokens keys logins
parallels and the like
directly
how here usually fit here well there
the three main ones can do nothing at all
encrypt as is Yes it is in fact
lack of security Can be again
encrypt with the ability to
registrar Yes Or we can
use third party key management
Store Yes, that's just what I think those who
was engaged in Application Security Pro KMS
directly knows Here is the same class
solution and exists for microservices
working in a cubernets cluster like this
this can be highlighted here
variety of approaches variations
implementation of work secrets in the province
Yeah starts how we'll be
directly and where to store this
the secret that we have
microservice could be
directly we have a variable
environment it could be
passed through the file which the application
will refer to read from a file Either
we can directly transfer it at once
same in memory in this way for example
attacking and otherwise caught
application will not understand what secrets how
extract them because they are not in the form of variables
environments not seeing files on file
the system in the environment of containers has nothing
we will not be at the same time also eat
directly various models
secrets they share with us class
tricubers on Push and on the pool model Yes
push model directly is when u
we really are in the cluster itself
such a special entity called
secret Yes task which in principle
store some sensitive information
here we have some essence
kubernets clusters and we have it there
is located, that is, the secret falls into itself
Cube storage as a separate resource
there is a pool-model this is when in the very
no additional
abstraction entity does not appear and already
the secret itself somehow pulls itself up
inside our
applications
thus, mechanisms are built in there
can be implemented through any of
children's library when at startup
app she just understands what to
for further work, she needs to contact
some external storage
class to another remedy get
from there these usage secrets in
further Yes it can be implemented
in the form directly to various
cubernets controllers that take and
various things themselves enclose though
in the governorate and absent inside
container popular approaches related
with a concept like sidekarmutation
when to our main container
which we are doing safe
adds a number of additional
containers and they will take over the tasks
related to adding a secret with his
update feedback rotation and so on
again, in the cube itself we do not have such
Essence like a secret but a extra
third-party components from third-party
external storage of secrets allows us
add them there directly Well, there is
for example the secret driver is executed as
dey and he shoves himself at
need
relevant secrets of your applications
so here you will need of course
sit with a team of architects
think about how you will be to this or that
applications approach directly to
delivery of that sensitive information And this
very important question because
developers are professionals who
maintain the system should not know
information especially from Production
the environment just needs to know how to get there
Connect to pick up
information and everything but the secrets themselves
later use it for
intentional goals they should not know
We go further all the application we have
dropped some secrets we have there
about injected passed interaction not
know with external databases very well and
etc. Yes now we move on to
the next stage we now have an application
works and we have to protect at runtime
And here you can share the whole story on
two large such levels
container directly
untime Security what is happening with us
inside the container what are the processes
how they interact
how they interact with each other
file system as they are
interact with the network Yes and
directly tail runtime Security
This is exactly what we have
happens Nastya here by ourselves
the possibilities that here you can separately
directly highlight it starting from
that we start by reducing
attack surface yes to the attacker
was even in the case directly
some compliment as little as possible
opportunities is all to deploy your
side and develop your attack Yes there is
as well as direct opportunities for
extra insulation when we do
such isolation that escape from it
gets even more complicated But that's about it
a little more directly more
classic this is our detection reaction
yes but detection just if we
for example inside the container started
Shell Yes, although it shouldn't be there, for example
be a prevention just not up to
run no other executables
files for example inside your container
and thus, for example, if even
the attacker has some kind of vulnerability
class repair code execution it just doesn't
will be able to run the desired Shell there
or another program Yes, there will be
strictly limited what can be run
what not to do well reaction reaction it's in
in terms of what we see what is already there
attackers we want to stop him
further actions we can there
for example stop container after pause
his and the like
here within the framework directly
a lot of cubernettis and containers
possible approaches Yes
At the same time, I would like to point out
What do I like about security?
engage in the framework is taken what he does not
sweeps aside what was done before him then
what is currently active with us
already used in the operating room itself
Linux system Yes and he directly
also allows us to control Linux to
beat with use profile sik
Parma profiles selinux profiles yes what
if you have already done security
operating system Link then these
mechanisms also to you directly
available and you can safely
use at home therefore the first
directly these things are mechanisms on
level of the same under the pit Yes and either
directly systemic mechanisms
Linux mechanisms Here we can
clearly limit the ability to reduce
And so the interface, for example, say that we have
this container only
has a ritual whether Root FS yes thereby
no extra things attacker
will not be able not to write not to rewrite
because he is purely on aridor either
generally take everything directly to
beat the dropol container do yes
thus if the attacker again
infiltrate make him escape through
vulnerability
tail operating system kernels
it will be extremely difficult
directly you can do a little
step back Yes, even before the launch, we
we can prepare an image of our
container in such a way that again
to the attacker in case of any
either vulnerabilities do deploy your
the attack will gain a foothold extremely
difficult Yes, for example, to do the same
image distroles yes either directly
just make a container based on scream
Yes, there will be only one go
binary and nothing else
the attacker would naturally like to have
Shell additional tool to
download download something scan
network but that's nothing there unfortunately a
there will be no following mechanism for it like
I spoke directly
extra isolation and governorate us
allows for flexible juggling
runtimes and we can not only
use the classic
containers based in groups of spaces
Yes, but we can use it separately
Sandbox micro notches Yes, therefore
cubernate will be able to
fact even manage they give more
high level of isolation but at the same time I
Separately, I note that in this case we lose
some observability Since if a
the classic container is essentially
Linux process processes with specific
properties then when we start
go to the level of son boxes and
microemok are separate groups of processes
and what passes there already for us
becomes obscure and hidden
directly behind these systemic
processes So if you want
understand what will happen to you
boxes and neighborhoods you'll have to
put additional agents there
very natural resources
inefficient use of the same
microemok and, in principle, sunboxes
usually require
makes demands on the iron itself
where it is run it should be either
Full verticalization or nested
virtualization If not, then they will
directly problems, since
specific hardbar required
processor capabilities for the hypervisor
which is used in the same
directly a world enki
and the next moment
common of those
are generally represented in the industry on the market
yes, these are agent systems that
placed on nodes on hosts they are like
the rule is put in the form Damon Seth Yes and
using ebpf technologies and at the same time
allows us to unmodify the environment
client without modifying directly
the microservices themselves behind which
observation capture all information that
it happens there and sees what is running there
how does it interact with receive
general immediate picture on
today seems to be the most
such an advanced way while it
gets along well with everyone
the above can be used
all together Yes, well, probably there is a conclusion
here is the insulation in the micro navy box yes there
epifa will not work for you, but that's all
the rest you can combine and
use together Here are the latest
case which I also meet
directly and for me he already is
deprecated legase Yes it is use
User Space components is more
looks like an antivirus
trying to replace part of your system
and through some injections through that
same LD prelo technique to add libraries
inside the containers and already there to happen
Observation first it works on
level L7 yes naturally attacking on
the same level Can turn it all off
it's very bad, as a rule
additional problems still appear
further safety Cast and nodes but
here basically if you were engaged
the security of Linux hosts is the same
the most but at the same time when we are already talking about
container registrar here
we have the next moment we
we can use either here is the operating
general purpose system which we all
we know well and we will have to
use the same kind of zoo
overhead solutions, which is very bad with
efficiency point of view
resources because they all require
resources and you are roughly out of eight
cores can just attachments
protection to give 3-4 cores there Yes, and on your
directly business logic will be there
half is not good at this these
general purpose operating systems
they are very big if you will
scan for a known vulnerability
get a giant report giant
reports gigantic work that's why
better approach today
is the use of specialized
operating systems are called
container specifics S which are sharpened
purely for launch directly to
containers, yes, that is, all of them were removed
directly what is not required for
launch containers, they have become smaller in
sizes Yes, and as a rule they
directly
tuned core for security and
they are his service cards, that is, even if
attackers will escape from such operating
from the container to the node with Where it is
content is something ok to do there
break develop his attack he will have
extremely difficult so if you
there is a possibility, it is desirable for
construction of governors is used
specialized operating systems
to run the container here is the following
big topic is network security
there are so many Giant desire
take some hardware firewall
put up a rack and make it work
protected the entire network in our clusters
provinces want to upset you but here
this is impossible here absolutely different
world a different approach and the fact that many
security professionals in particular
juice experts are upset by the fact that
ip address here changes goes from
start to start one microservice to
to another so build some rules
and correlations based on IP addresses by
in relation to microservices in principle
dead and non-working system will have to
get tied up on higher levels you
essence here with all the security
cubernation cluster networks we can
divide by
caste host network security
because the hosts of the node we have is in
same subnet and network directly
codes They are on a different subnet and
we can directly do there
host policies and directly
policies for occasion
while here we can use
approaches related to white-sheets and
black-sheets only as we
allowed only so they will work
relative tasks Let's talk about
segmentation Well to date
There are three ways to
direct use of
cubernets native firewall is
the best and most efficient
resource-efficient way Yes it is Network
policy At the same time, we have two
types are native data these format
politician and directly custom from
each of the hay providers that you
you can choose yourself
use several at the same time
native custom policies
thanks to them you can
configure even the Network Police host
explain how you hosts to each other
will communicate And so the most popular
case we clearly explain that the service
communicates with service b on a certain port
b-smc service for such and such everything even if
an attacker penetrates service a
the best he can do
contact service b on the authorized
port so this is the most popular way
how to do segmentation in a cluster
the second path is taken, which in principle
does not cancel the first can only
enhance and supplement at the level of service
meshes they are now actively developing they are
allow to do
many interesting things but
principle
now the service mesh even with their stages
development becomes part of the same network
the same shinai so I think soon
such a class solution as the Smash service
generally disappears directly because
that he is quite
resource-intensive in current implementations
requires additional containers for
each of your container
naturally consumes inefficiently
resources now they are becoming more and more
the functionality of the same Sinai is
another path that can be found in
part of the solution is when implemented
again own implementation Yes it is
some userspace on and hooks interceptions
library injections In general, such
classical anti-virus approaches from
nineties but already in containers they
also removed bypass here and by
performance They are certainly worse than
native ways that I listed
you higher
next moment it's directly
control of incoming outgoing traffic Yes
we can have a closed loop with us
can only be directly